<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">

<ags:resource ags:ARN="PH2007000715">
		<dc:title xml:lang="en">Participatory land use planning in Kaliwa Watershed, Tanay, Rizal (Philippines)</dc:title>
		<dc:creator>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Racelis, D. A.,Philippines Univ. Los Baños, College Laguna (Philippines)  Coll. of Forestry and Natural Resources</ags:creatorPersonal>
			<ags:creatorConference>2005 Symposium of the Forests and Natural Resources Research Society of the Philippines, Inc., , College, Laguna (Philippines), 30 Nov - 1 Dec 2005</ags:creatorConference>
		</dc:creator>
		<dc:publisher>
			<ags:publisherPlace>College, Laguna  (Philippines)</ags:publisherPlace>
		</dc:publisher>
		<dc:date>
			<dcterms:dateIssued>2005</dcterms:dateIssued>
		</dc:date>
		<dc:subject>
			<ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E11</ags:subjectClassification>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">WATERSHEDS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND USE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">PLANNING</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">RURAL COMMUNITIES</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">SOCIAL PARTICIPATION</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">PHILIPPINES</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">BASSIN VERSANT</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">UTILISATION DES TERRES</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">PLANIFICATION</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">COMMUNAUTE RURALE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">PARTICIPATION SOCIALE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">PARTICIPATION COMMUNAUTAIRE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">PHILIPPINES</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">CUENCAS HIDROGRAFICAS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">UTILIZACION DE LA TIERRA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">PLANIFICACION</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">COMUNIDADES RURALES</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">PARTICIPACION SOCIAL</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">PARTICIPACION COMUNITARIA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">FILIPINAS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_8334</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_4182</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_5951</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_6700</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_14373</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_37559</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_5783</ags:subjectThesaurus>
		</dc:subject>
		<dc:description>
			<ags:descriptionNotes>Summary only</ags:descriptionNotes>
			<ags:descriptionNotes>Received May 2006</ags:descriptionNotes>
			<dcterms:abstract xml:lang="En">A participatory land use zoning project was implemented in 8 barangays [villages] in the Kaliwa Watershed. It essentially involved the determination and identification of socially equitable, environmentally acceptable and economically feasible land uses. Such an approach could ensure the sustainability of identified land uses and at the same time promote the general welfare and empower communities in sustainably managing the watershed. Specifically, it aimed to: a) delineate the boundaries of the 8 barangays in the Kaliwa watershed; b) delineate barangay land use zones; c) prepare barangays 3D land use maps; d) formulate prescriptions and regulations for the use of the land use zones in the barangays; and e) establish land use demonstration sites to showcase sustainable land use systems in the watershed. The project consisted of three major components including: a) survey and mapping; b) participatory land use; and c) land use demonstration. The survey and mapping component involved the delineation and mapping of barangay boundaries, and delineation of barangay land use zones, and participatory 3D land use mapping. Participatory land use planning included training and capacitating locals in carrying out barangay land use planning, formulation and legitimization of prescriptions and regulations for the use of land use zones, and preparation and legitimization of land use plans. Land use demonstration enabled the showcased field level intervention to improve current land uses. The respective current land use maps of the barangays were prepared and updated. Surveys were made to define the extent of existing land uses and define the respective boundaries of the barangays. Field surveys showed that boundary conflicts exist among most of the barangays in the watershed. Technical descriptions of the boundaries were generated using topographic maps, remote sensing data and field survey data. Land use planning teams were organized in each barangay to facilitate the implementation and institutionalization of participatory land use planning at the community level. A series of planning to familiarize the local communities on the fundamentals of participatory land use planning. Focused group discussions were also conducted to gather relevant data and define the perceptions of local communities with regard to resource use and land use zoning. Each barangay was able to formulate their respective land use guidelines and prescriptions, which they used to formulate the indicative barangay land use plan. The land use guidelines and criteria were also used to identify the proposed land uses per barangay. The land use guidelines and  land use plans were endorsed by the respective barangay councils through a resolution. They were also endorsed to the municipal council for proper affirmation. The feasibility of proposed land uses were determined through erosion modeling. Results showed that land use zoning could significantly improve the sustainability of the watershed. Comparison between current and proposed land uses indicated that erosion is lower if land use zoning is adapted. The proposed land uses particularly protection forests and agroforestry are desirable land uses that could mitigate soil erosion. Eight 3D land use maps were developed to facilitate the implementation of land use zoning in the barangays. Four land use demonstration sites were successfully established including alley-cropping/ agroforestry/ fruit orchard-mango plantation, reforestation-mixed planting, and assisted natural regeneration.</dcterms:abstract>
		</dc:description>
		<dc:type>K</dc:type>
		<dc:type>V</dc:type>
		<dc:type>E</dc:type>
		<dc:format>
			<dcterms:extent>p. 20</dcterms:extent>
		</dc:format>
		<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
		<agls:availability>
			<ags:availabilityLocation>*UPLB Main Library, College Laguna  (Philippines)</ags:availabilityLocation>
			<ags:availabilityNumber>2007000715</ags:availabilityNumber>
		</agls:availability>
		<dc:source>New Frontiers in Forest and Natural Resources Research: Abstracts of Papers, Forests and Natural Resources Research Society of the Philippines, Inc., College, Laguna (Philippines).- College, Laguna  (Philippines), 2005. 2005 Symposium of the Forests and Natural Resources Research Society of the Philippines, Inc.,2005 Symposium of the Forests and Natural Resources Research Society of the Philippines, Inc., College, Laguna (Philippines), 30 Nov - 1 Dec 2005.- p. 20</dc:source>
	</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="GB2013203715">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Land reform, agriculture and poverty reduction]]></dc:title>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Department for International Development, UK]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued>2004</dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land reform]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land redistribution]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure.Land registration]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure.Communal land]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land policies]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Poverty]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[tenure]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Africa]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land reform]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Economic growth]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[South Africa]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land use]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land administration]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description>
		<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[What we know and don't know about land reform for poverty reduction]]></ags:descriptionNotes></dc:description>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Most land-based livelihoods rely on having secure access to land, a precondition for sustainable agriculture, economic growth and poverty reduction. This working paper examines the state of knowledge with regard to aspects of land reform- redistributive reform, land tenure reform, and the issue of land markets.  It also addresses issues that remain unknown in areas of land and social equity, land administration, and land tax.Redistributive land reform aims to bring about an equitable distribution of land and the political power emanating from it. Past results have been less than impressive, and agrarian restructuring has been very slow.Tenure reform, has been plagued by a failure to appreciate the complex and highly contested nature of land issues in post-colonial states. The paper notes that land policy reform is unlikely to have significant poverty reducing effects unless attention is paid to institutional capacity building.Efficient transactions in land markets can encourage the transfer of land from less productive to more productive use, but excessive state regulation and bureaucracy are often the norm. Temporary transfers through land rental are an important redistribution mechanism. Rental markets- an important redistribution mechanism- have lower transaction costs and can help households deal with shocks or stresses without loss of productive assets.What don’t we still know about land reform? The following pertinent questions remain:what are the precise transmission mechanisms by which land reform contributes to poverty reduction?what are the synergies and/or trade-offs between greater equality in land ownership and increasing agricultural growth for poverty reduction?what kinds of land transfers can be carried out within land administration for improved growth and poverty outcomes in agriculture?how do current land administration arrangements prevent land transfers for positive growth and poverty reduction?what sorts of revised approaches to land administration are best, and how can they be designed and implemented?what forms of land and production taxes are most likely to encourage increases in agricultural productivity?how can land taxation systems be designed so they do not discourage investments by small-scale farmers, and under what circumstances is this appropriate? ]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://dfid-agriculture-consultation.nri.org/summaries/wp5.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.eldis.org/vfile/upload/1/document/0708/DOC19660.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:language><![CDATA[English]]></dc:language>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QV2005000042">

<dc:title xml:lang="en">Land cover and land use in Syria: An overview</dc:title>

<dc:creator>

<ags:creatorPersonal>De Pauw, E.</ags:creatorPersonal>

<ags:creatorPersonal>Oberle, A.</ags:creatorPersonal>

<ags:creatorPersonal>Zoebisch, M. (ICARDA, Aleppo (Syria))</ags:creatorPersonal>

<ags:creatorCorporate>Asian Institute of Technology (AIT), Klong Luang, Pathumthani (Thailand)</ags:creatorCorporate>

<ags:creatorCorporate>World Association of Soil and Water Conservation (WASWC), Beijing (China)</ags:creatorCorporate>

<ags:creatorCorporate>International Center for Agricultural Research in the Dry Areas, Aleppo (Syria)</ags:creatorCorporate>

</dc:creator>

<dc:publisher><ags:publisherName>Asian Institute of Technology - AIT</ags:publisherName>

<ags:publisherPlace>Klong Luang, Pathumthani (Thailand)</ags:publisherPlace>

</dc:publisher>

<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued>2004</dcterms:dateIssued>

</dc:date>

<dc:subject>

<ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">P01</ags:subjectClassification>

<ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E11</ags:subjectClassification>

<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND USE</ags:subjectThesaurus>

<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">VEGETATION</ags:subjectThesaurus>

<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND MANAGEMENT</ags:subjectThesaurus>

<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND CLASSIFICATION</ags:subjectThesaurus>

<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">GEOGRAPHICAL INFORMATION SYSTEMS</ags:subjectThesaurus>

<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">REMOTE SENSING</ags:subjectThesaurus>

<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND DEGRADATION</ags:subjectThesaurus>

<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">CARTOGRAPHY</ags:subjectThesaurus>

<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">COVER PLANTS</ags:subjectThesaurus>

<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">ECOLOGY</ags:subjectThesaurus>

<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">SYRIA</ags:subjectThesaurus>

</dc:subject>

<dc:description>

<ags:descriptionNotes>Ref., maps</ags:descriptionNotes>

<dcterms:abstract xml:lang="En">This research report presents a study of land cover and land use in Syria as it existed during the period 1989/1990. It is based on an interpretation of satellite-derived products (Landsat 5 TM hardcopy images) and field checking. The main product is a Land Use/Land Cover map of Syria for the base year 1989/1990. The major source of information was Syria Space Image Atlas prepared by the General Organization of Remote Sensing in Syria (GORS). For this land cover/land use map a local and a-posteriori classification system was selected, and incorporating elements of both land cover and of land use. Map compilation was essentially a GIS exercise, based on visual interpretation of observed features. The map legend consists of two main classes: homogeneous units, which can be considered relatively pure (80-90%), and mixed units, which are complexes of homogeneous units. Twenty four homogeneous classes were differentiated on the basis of the following major categories: (i) bare areas with or without sparse cover, (ii) cultivated areas, (iii) forests and other wooded areas, (iv) rangelands, (v) urbanized areas, (vi) water bodies. In addition, 43 mixed classes were distinguished. For the base year 1989/1990 about one third of Syria (about 34%) was cultivated, mostly under rainfed systems. Considering the semi-arid or arid conditions in the country, this is a very high proportion of agriculture to the total land area. Of the cultivated area, about 8,000 km2 was irrigated. This is probably an underestimation, and, if the areas are included of mixed units in which irrigated land use occurs as a minority land use, a total estimate of about 11,500 km2 of irrigated land was obtained. Forested or wooded areas had a very limited extent in the country, about three percent. Overall there is a good agreement between the land use estimates obtained from the remote sensing interpretation and statistics derived from the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations database, FAOSTAT. However, some allowance needs to be made for features that can not be 'seen' but recorded in official statistics as 'land use'. The most conspicuous case is for the rangelands, which receive a rather low tally as a separate category from the image interpretation, but a high one in the FAO statistics. The explanation for this discrepancy is simply that many 'bare' lands are grazed during part of the year, but that this land use  cannot be observed, only inferred, given its lack of visibility on summer imagery. If bare lands and rangelands are lumped together, the correspondence between estimates from remote sensing and production statistics is quite good. Another interesting finding is the good correspondence between land cover/land use patterns and the major physical regions of Syria. The imagery used for this study allows drawing only limited, but useful, conclusions about the prevalence of land degradation and the current activity of degradation processes. In addition, it is not always easy to separate those forms of degradation that are entirely natural from those that are man-made. Three forms of land degradation processes could be identified or inferred from the imagery: (i) vegetation degradation, (ii) wind and water erosion, and (iii) salinization. The current land cover/land use map has applications in land use planning and research related to the characterization and evolution of production systems and land degradation. The approach to land cover/land use mapping, based on manual interpretation of a hardcopy image product, while perfectly acceptable at the time to achieve a high-priority research goal in a short time under prevailing constraints of data products and budgets, will probably not be replicated in the future. With the cost of medium-resolution imagery dropping markedly over the last few years, and image analysis software becoming cheaper, more powerful and user-friendly, it is unavoidable that any new land cover/land use mapping will be based on image analysis rather than manual interpretation. Given the rapid rate of change in the rural environments of Syria, an update on the land cover/land use situation is urgently needed for the period 2000-2005</dcterms:abstract>

</dc:description><dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">974-92678-8-5</dc:identifier>

<dc:type>V</dc:type>

<dc:format><dcterms:extent>47 p.</dcterms:extent></dc:format>

<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>

<agls:availability><ags:availabilityLocation>QV</ags:availabilityLocation><ags:availabilityNumber>*QV. E-mail: LIBRARY-ICARDA@CGIAR.ORG Kamal Hindawi</ags:availabilityNumber></agls:availability>

</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="GB2013202629">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Land rights for African development: from knowledge to action]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E. Mwangi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E. Patrick]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CGIAR System-wide Program on Property Rights and Collective Action]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued>2006</dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Rosalie Kingwill]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Clarissa Augustinus]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Rural development]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Legal Dualism and Land Policy in Eastern and Southern Africa]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Legal Pluralism as a Policy Option: Is it Desirable? Is it Doable?]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Donna Hornby]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Questioning the Mythologies of Hernando de Soto]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Liz Alden Wily]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure.Land registration]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Getting the Process Right: The Experience of the Uganda Lan]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Biting the Bullet: How to Secure Access to Drylands Resources for Multiple Users]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[The Commons and Customary Law in Modern Times: Rethinking the Orthodoxies]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure.Communal land]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Joan Kagwanja]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Patrick McAuslan]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Gender Issues in Land Tenure under Customary law]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Lauren Royston]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Will Formalizing Property Rights Reduce Poverty in South Africa’s “Second Economy”?]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Esther Mwangi]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Stephan Dohrn]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Klaus Deininger]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Ben Cousins]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Land Tenure, Land Reform, and the Management of Land and Natural Resources in Africa]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Stephen Turner]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Hubert M.G. Ouedraogo]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Martin Adams]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Warren Smit]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Patricia Kameri-Mbote]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovations in Land Tenure, Reform and Administration in Africa]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Tessa Cousins]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Decentralization: An Enabling Policy for Local Land Management]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land policies]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land management]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Right of access]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Role of women]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[tenure]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[legislation]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[legal rights]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land rights]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[women]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[decentralization]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description>
		<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Land tenure innovations required to secure sustainable rural development]]></ags:descriptionNotes></dc:description>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[This collection of briefing papers summarises select papers presented at the workshop: "Land Rights for African Development: From Knowledge to Action" held in November 2005. The workshop addressed key land tenure issues in Africa that influence food security, environmental sustainability, agricultural intensification, conflict, peace building and broader rural development.Issues covered by the 12 briefing papers contained in this collection include: the prevalence and importance of customary tenurethe prevalence and importance of common property arrangementsconstraints to women’s access under both customary and statutory tenurethe need to secure common property and other forms of tenurethe importance of broad based participation to secure broad consensus among multiple actors in order to enhance the efficiency, equity and sustainability objectives of land tenure reforms.The briefing papers also reflect on the innovations necessary for securing tenure for the poor under a variety of settings. These innovations include:adjusting received law to customary norms and rules of land holding and access, as opposed to outright replacing customary tenurealtering lending rules by banks and financial institutions to promote land-related investments (even on land regulated by customary and/or religious law)de-emphasising the notion of ownership and refocusing on use rights in order to secure women’s rights and accessrestructuring conventional land administration systems to support group-based rights structuresencouraging decentralised land management systems that reflect local cultural norms and practicesin situations of multiple, overlapping resource use, strengthening processes of negotiation and conflict resolution as opposed to a generic concern with substantive rights in order to secure the access of permanent and transitory resource users.A ten-step procedure is also suggested (Alden Wily), which would enable communities to restore their group rights and practices to create and control their own tenure norms. These innovations, while desirable, are also risky: corruption, elite capture, exclusion of "non-members" and lack of capacities have been hurdles faced by communities.Agreed outcomes from the workshop include the following:land tenure in Africa is complex: the existence of customary, religious and statutory arrangements (i.e. legal pluralism) is a critical, defining feature of African land tenure. Land tenure reform must accommodate this complexity rather than replace itthe pit-falls of formalisation should be avoided, and in particular tenure codification should be delinked from collateralisation: cheaper ways of registering rights than the cadastre are neededin order to effectively address land tenure security, power issues at local and national levels must be addressed: there is a need for a multi-level, multiple actor approach. Land tenure reform is an urgent governance issue that can best be addressed by all development partners in collaborationon evaluation: the implementation and impacts of land tenure reforms should be evaluated at multiple governance levels in order to identify constraints, craft solutions, and to ensure that reforms are securing the rights and livelihoods of women, the poor and marginalised groupson innovation: new innovations are needed over and above tinkering with existing possibilities. For instance, the development of centres for legal advice and assistance for both rural and urban dwellers may enable the poor to claim their rights and even challenge abuses of power. ]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.capri.cgiar.org/pdf/brief_land.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:language><![CDATA[English]]></dc:language>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="US2012406969">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[GEF Land Degradation Linkage Study]]></dc:title>
	<dc:title>
		<ags:titleSupplement><![CDATA[GEF Land Degradation Linkage Study]]></ags:titleSupplement>
	</dc:title>
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Berry, Leonard; Olson, Jennifer;]]></dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorCorporate><![CDATA[Global Envirnmt Facility Secretr (GEF)]]></ags:creatorCorporate>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[The World Bank]]></ags:publisherName>
		<ags:publisherPlace><![CDATA[Washington, DC (USA)]]></ags:publisherPlace>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land degradation]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Carbon]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land management]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Degradation]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Biodiversity]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Protected areas]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Forecasting]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Climatic change]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land use]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The purpose of this report is to   identify the results, and initial impact of the land   degradation component of those linkage projects which   encompass biodiversity, international waters, and climate   change with land degradation. The lessons learned from this   review lead to recommendations on how land degradation   issues should be addressed in focal area reviews, and in   subsequent Global Environment Facility (GEF) activities. In   general, the detailed study of project documents shows that   the land degradation component of projects is not as strong   as suggested in previous GEF reports, though this desk   analysis may not reveal actual field-level actions, and   priorities. It is clear, however, that the number of land   degradation projects, and financial allocation to land   degradation, has not increased in recent years, with the   exception of medium-size projects. An initial analysis of   this trend suggests some basic causes, which have limited   land degradation linkage activities: project concepts are   usually based on focal area activities, rather than linkage   activities such as land degradation; 69 percent of projects   with land degradation linkages are in the biodiversity focal   area, of which 77 percent are located in, or near protected   conservation areas, not usually regions of the highest land   degradation concern; international waters projects have   included land degradation mitigation in some cases, but the   specifics have tended to focus on institutional, and water   pollution aspects, rather than land degradation, mitigation,   and catchment management activities; climate change projects   have not in recent years, focused much on land degradation   because current climate change operational programs are not   addressing land management issues, though there seem to be   opportunities to expand this linkage with a new operational   program; and finally, the difficulty in estimating   incremental costs of mitigation activities, when the   activities are usually providing local, as well as global   benefits. The review of project documents did provide some   clear findings: GEF projects with a strong land degradation   component are fewer than previously thought, revealing   projects containing a strong land degradation component have   been allocated about US$278 million by the GEF, though the   portion that comprises the land degradation component is   estimated at US$50 million of the GEF portfolio. Moreover,   the most effective linkage projects appear to be those where   land degradation is built in as an initial component of the   problem, and the solution. And, in biodiversity linkage   projects, rangeland environments have created the best land   degradation/biodiversity synergy. A for international waters   projects, land issues - while included - have been generally   given less prominence in project implementation, and,   projects with a people/land management focus tend to address   land degradation issues more directly.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:RN"><![CDATA[26666]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[1-884122-81-7]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www-wds.worldbank.org/servlet/WDSContentServer/IW3P/IB/2003/09/03/000012009_20030903113957/Rendered/PDF/266660Monitoring010Evaluation0no.06.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Working Paper (Numbered Series)]]></dc:type>
	<dc:language scheme="dcterms:ISO639-2"><![CDATA[eng]]></dc:language>
	<dc:source><![CDATA[1 of 1]]></dc:source>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[World]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[GEF Monitoring and Evaluation working paper
            ; no. 6]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1020-894;</ags:citationIdentifier>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="GB2013202724">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Seeking ways out of the impasse on land reform in Southern Africa: notes from an informal ‘think tank’ meeting]]></dc:title>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Oxfam]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued>2003</dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[HIV.Treatment and care]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land reform]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land rights]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[women]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[rural]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[HIV/AIDS]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[customary land rights]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[gender mainstreaming]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Southern Africa]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[gender]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land redistribution]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[HIV]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Labour]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[water supply]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[foods]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Poverty]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Role of women]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Disasters]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Development aid]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Climatic change]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[women]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Natural disasters]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description>
		<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[What are the key issues surrounding land reform in Southern Africa?]]></ags:descriptionNotes></dc:description>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Land reform in Southern Africa is currently at an impasse.  This paper analyses the constraints to sustainable land reform and identifies ways and means of moving things forward.  In addition, appendices to the document include country by country reviews of the status of land reform in each country, and a matrix providing an overview of current land issues in the region.The document finds that whilst some progress has been achieved with tenure reform in Botswana, Malawi and Mozambique, many challenges remain across the region, particularly for Zimbabwe, South Africa and Namibia.  The paper finds that the following issues need to be understood and addressed:Cyclical patterns of land reform in the region:initial strong political commitment to land redistribution often gives way to an emphasis on ‘economic’ goals rather than the eradication of poverty, which tends to favour elite landowners rather than the landless lobby.Redistributive land reform:in the context of the region, and in particular South Africa, the following need to be addressed:balancing redistribution with sustainable rural developmentthe productivity of small farmersestablishing post-transfer support (farm credit, extension services) in complex institutional contextshigh rural to urban migrationmobilisation for change amongst civil society and businessthe possibility of dropping the ‘willing buyer, willing seller’ approachLand tenure reform:is a crucial issue as it may assure the land rights of the majority of the population, because of the potential link between secure land rights, investment and economic growth, and because it is an important safeguard against creating land or income inequality in the future.Land rights of women:across the region, women suffer from strong male bias in relation to land rights. Despite pockets of success (for example Botswana), there is insufficient attention to mainstreaming gender concerns into land policy and implementation. This applies not only to governments and public and customary institutions, but also to many donor and NGO programmes.Customary land rights and systems:initiatives to protect customary land rights alongside formal rights in polarised and racially divided contexts such as Zimbabwe, South Africa and Namibia can benefit from looking at the experiences of lower profile countries of Botswana, Mozambique and Malawi.  Emphasis should be placed upon the process (who is involved in the policy discussions and subsequent implementation) as much as the technical content and substance of the resulting programme.HIV/AIDS and land:the potentially catastrophic impact of HIV/AIDS requires a re-examination of many basic assumptions underpinning land policy work.  The pandemic is bringing the negative impact of aspects of customary law on the livelihoods of women and children into sharper focus, as their land rights become more vulnerable to dispossession by patrilineal kin on the death of male household heads. More attention needs to be paid to understanding the impact of HIV/AIDS on land tenure.Donor support to government land reform programmes is increasingly politically sensitive for both donors and recipient governments. However, donors should continue to support a redistribution agenda, which should be a long-term iterative process, requiring feedback, learning and involvement of many stakeholders.Donor support to civil society initiativesshould be further encouraged, for example through a ‘Land Reform Fund’. Civil society organisations are a source of knowledge and information, are effective partners in implementing land reform, and can also be important in kick-starting new government initiatives. ]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.oxfam.org.uk/what_we_do/issues/livelihoods/landrights/downloads/impassertf.rtf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:language><![CDATA[English]]></dc:language>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="JP1999006974">
<dc:title xml:lang="en">Relationships between recent land-use change and legal land-use classification in the area of greater Sapporo [Japan]</dc:title>
<dc:creator>
<ags:creatorPersonal>Yazawa, M. (Hokkaido Univ., Sapporo (Japan))</ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal>Takatsuki, D.</ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal>Wang, X.</ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal>Horiguchi, I.</ags:creatorPersonal>
</dc:creator>
<dc:date>
<dcterms:dateIssued>(Feb 1999)</dcterms:dateIssued>
</dc:date>
<dc:subject>
<ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E11</ags:subjectClassification>
<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND USE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">URBAN AREAS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">JAPAN</ags:subjectThesaurus>
<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">TRENDS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND CLASSIFICATION</ags:subjectThesaurus>
<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LEGAL LIABILITY</ags:subjectThesaurus>
<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">UTILISATION DES TERRES</ags:subjectThesaurus>
<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">ZONE URBAINE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">JAPON</ags:subjectThesaurus>
<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">TENDANCE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">CLASSIFICATION DES TERRES</ags:subjectThesaurus>
<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">RESPONSABILITE LEGALE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">UTILIZACION DE LA TIERRA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">ZONAS URBANAS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">JAPON</ags:subjectThesaurus>
<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">TENDENCIAS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">CLASIFICACION DE TIERRAS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">RESPONSABILIDAD LEGAL</ags:subjectThesaurus>
</dc:subject>
<dc:description><ags:descriptionNotes>Summary (En)</ags:descriptionNotes>
<ags:descriptionNotes>4 tables; 11 fig.; 6 ref</ags:descriptionNotes>
<dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Recent land-use changes in expanding urban areas were studied by using two land-use area files (1976 file and 1991 file) of the Digital National Land Information in Japan.  The purpose of this study was to clarify the relationship of increases and decreases in the use of four land types (agricultural land, urban land, barren land, natural land) to the legal land-use classification.  The areas studied were seven municipalities in the area of greater Sapporo (Sapporo City, Ebetsu City, Chitose City, Eniwa City, Kita-Hiroshima City, Ishikari City, Tobetsu. Town).  Urban land-use significantly increased in all of the seven study areas, while the use of agricultural and natural land decreased in varying degrees in the study areas: a notable decrease in agricultural land-use in four municipalities (Sapporo City, Ebetsu City, Eniwa City and Ishikari City), a notable decrease in the use of natural land (mainly forest land) in two municipalities (Chitose City and Tobetsu Town), and a similar degree of decrease in the use of agricultural and natural land in Kita-Hiroshima City.  The area of barren land increased in three municipalities (Sapporo City, Kita-Hiroshima City and Ishikari City) and decreased in the other four municipalities.  The area of land-use change was greatest in Sapporo City, followed by Ishikari City, chitose City and Ebetsu City.  In terms of population, the area of land-use change was greatest in Ishikari City.  In terms of legal land-use classification, land-use change was greatest in the urbanization-promotion area of five municipalities (Sapporo City, Ebetsu City, Eniwa City, Kita-Hiroshima City and Ishikari City), while the greatest changes in land-use in tobetsu Town and chitose City were in the agricultural land zone and in the area of other land, respectively.  In many of the municipalities, the second-greatest area of land-use change was in the white zone of the agriculture-promotion area</dcterms:abstract>
</dc:description>
<dc:type>E</dc:type>
<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
<agls:availability><ags:availabilityLocation>JP</ags:availabilityLocation><ags:availabilityNumber>1999006974</ags:availabilityNumber></agls:availability>
<ags:citation><ags:citationTitle>Journal of the Faculty of Agriculture - Hokkaido University (Japan)</ags:citationTitle>
<ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">0018-344X</ags:citationIdentifier>
<ags:citationNumber>v. 69(1) p. 31-45</ags:citationNumber>
<ags:citationChronology>(Feb 1999)</ags:citationChronology>
</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QM2008000116">
		<dc:title xml:lang="en">From land cover change to land function dynamics: a major challenge to improve land characterization</dc:title>
		<dc:creator>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Verburg, P.H..</ags:creatorPersonal>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Steeg, J. van de</ags:creatorPersonal>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Veldkamp, A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Willemen, L.</ags:creatorPersonal>
		</dc:creator>
		<dc:date>
			<dcterms:dateIssued>2008</dcterms:dateIssued>
		</dc:date>
		<dc:subject>
			<ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E11</ags:subjectClassification>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND USE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">PLANT COVER</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">ECOSYSTEMS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">SERVICES</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">MODELS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">MONITORING</ags:subjectThesaurus>
		</dc:subject>
		<dc:description>
			<dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Land cover change has always had a central role in land change science. This central role is largely the result of the possibilities to map and characterize land cover based on observations and remote sensing. This paper argues that more attention should be given to land use and land functions and linkages between these. Consideration of land functions that provide a wide range of goods and services makes more integrated assessments of land change possible. The increasing attention to multifunctional land use is another incentive to develop methods to assess changes in land functions. A number of methods to quantify and map the spatial extent of land use and land functions are discussed and the implications for modeling are identified based on recent model approaches in land change science. The mixed use of land cover, land use and land function in maps and models leads to inconsistencies in land change assessments. Explicit attention to the non-linear relations between land cover, land use and land function is essential to consistently address land change. New methods to map and quantify land function dynamics will enhance our ability to understand and model land system change and adequately inform policies and planning.
science; Multi functional land use</dcterms:abstract>
		</dc:description>
		<dc:type>Reprint</dc:type>
		<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
		<agls:availability>
			<ags:availabilityLocation>QM</ags:availabilityLocation>
			<ags:availabilityNumber>7920</ags:availabilityNumber>
		</agls:availability>
		<ags:citation>
			<ags:citationTitle>Journal of Environmental Management</ags:citationTitle>
			<ags:citationNumber>In Press</ags:citationNumber>
			<ags:citationChronology>2008</ags:citationChronology>
		</ags:citation>
	</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="GB2013201938">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Modes of land access and welfare impacts in Uganda]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A. Tatwangire]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S. T. Holden]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Norwegian University of Life Sciences]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued>2009</dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[poverty reduction]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Norway.Agriculture]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land markets]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Uganda]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Norway]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[markets]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Poverty]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land access]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Marketing]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[market access]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[welfare]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Uganda]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[surveying]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Models]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description>
		<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Do land markets contribute to poverty reduction?]]></ags:descriptionNotes></dc:description>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[This paper estimates the poverty reducing impact of land access in rural Uganda. The paper firstly states that land acquired through markets or otherwise may play an important role for rural household welfare. Conversely, there are concerns that poverty reduction effect of access to land through the market may be inadequate, due to land markets that can increase land concentration among the rich and inefficient producers. In this context, the paper argues that poverty reduction effect of land can be effective when more efficient farmers are able to acquire additional land through a mode of land access with stronger welfare increasing effects.<br /><br />The paper notes that land, whether accessed through the market or not, is an important determinant of household welfare. Indeed, households with more of owned land, operated land, or market-accessed land would gain a significant welfare-improving effect of better land access. However, this is conditioned to controlling for both endogeneity in land access and unobserved heterogeneity effects on welfare. <br /><br />The paper's findings indicate significant poverty reduction effects of increased land access in form of owned, operated and market-accessed land. Furthermore, the poverty reduction effect for land accessed through the market was significantly larger than the poverty reduction effect of land accessed through inheritance. The paper argues that this is likely to be the case because land markets, to a larger extent, transfer land to more efficient producers. The paper concludes that land markets enhance efficiency as well as contribute to poverty reduction. ]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.umb.no/statisk/ncde-2009/alex_tatwangire.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:language><![CDATA[English]]></dc:language>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Uganda]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="GB2013203480">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Reassessing Kenya's land reform]]></dc:title>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Institute of Economic Affairs, Kenya]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued>2000</dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Land reform]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[corruption]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Redistribution]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[povgdn]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[law]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Kenya]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Poverty]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land ownership]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[tenure]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[farmland]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land reform]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land economics]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land use]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description>
		<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[How should Kenyan land reform be conducted?]]></ags:descriptionNotes></dc:description>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[This article discusses issues surrounding land reform in Kenya. As the nature of land reforms is as yet undecided, disparate suggestions and proposals are being considered. These include:<B>Land Ownership Ceilings.</B> There are vast inequalities in land ownership. Indeed, non-indigenous Kenyans or corporations that are not significantly Kenyan own the largest consolidated quantities of Kenyan lands. Ceilings on land ownership, would encourage more equitable distribution of land, perhaps facilitating more effective production and a  reduction in food security problems. Such a move will naturally interfere with individual property rights.<B>Land sub-division</B> is a common phenomena in productive agricultural areas of Kenya. This provokes an increasingly unproductive agricultural sector, consisting of uneconomical units with diminishing returns and overall declining value. In this context, the article suggests that restrictions may need to be set on such fragmentation. This may be problematic for several reasons:Such restrictions would interfere with individual property rights and freedom of useA distinction must be made between the negative effects of fragmentation of agricultural land and sub-division of non-agricultural land, which may be beneficialAs a consequence of these two potential problems, it may be more acceptable to encourage land consolidationUnrestricted freedom of ownership should be encouraged. Land should be considered as a resource, which is subject to sale like any other commodity. Within a culturally diverse nation such as Kenya, it is important that regional monocultures are not encouraged by restricting land ownership to specific ethnic or racial communities.Ethnic land rights should be respected, requiring a restriction of entitlement of the acquisition by individuals/groups that are not affiliated with the specific community, ethnicity or race associated with a particular locationAs a result of the government abusing its powers of trusteeship over the public asset of the land, the government should cede control of public land to a custodian of public assets answerable to parliament.Land law should be simplified<B>Conclusions:</B>Land reform issues remain complicated by reasons ranging from legal complexities, political involvement, corruption and the extreme poverty in the countryGiven the present circumstances, the arguments proposing the restriction on land ownership with regard to ethnic and racial size will lead to retrogressive and unacceptable social and economic outcomes.While meaningful land reform is necessary, it can only be meaningful as a component of wider economic reform [Author] ]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.eldis.org/fulltext/land.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.eldis.org/vfile/upload/1/document/0708/DOC8151.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:language><![CDATA[English]]></dc:language>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Kenya]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="PH8811859">
<dc:title xml:lang="en">Interactive land-use planning algorithm [Philippines]</dc:title>
<dc:creator>
<ags:creatorPersonal>Balanque, T.O.</ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorCorporate>Philippines Univ., Los Banos, College, Laguna (Philippines)</ags:creatorCorporate>
</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher><ags:publisherPlace>College, Laguna (Philippines)</ags:publisherPlace>
</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>
<dcterms:dateIssued>May 1988</dcterms:dateIssued>
</dc:date>
<dc:subject>
<ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">U10</ags:subjectClassification>
<ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E11</ags:subjectClassification>
<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">MODELE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">UTILISATION DU SOL</ags:subjectThesaurus>
<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">PHILIPPINES</ags:subjectThesaurus>
<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">MODELOS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">UTILIZACION DE LA TIERRA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">FILIPINAS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
</dc:subject>
<dc:description><ags:descriptionNotes>97 graphs; 44 tables; 45 ref. Summaries (En). Appendices. Received Jun 1988. *PH</ags:descriptionNotes>
<dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">An interactive land-use planning algorithm is developed for biophysical data management system, land capability assessment, land suitability assessment, land-use evaluation, and land-use allocation. The algorithm is an effective land use planning tool because of its speed to provide important land capability, land suitability, and land-use allocation information and maps for land-use planning, decision making, and land management. The algorithm was validated in the planning of major land uses with Davao del Norte [Philippines] as study area. It mapped several biophysical factors; overlayed by the factor maps, identified land response units, identified land capabilities, assessed land suitabilities, evaluated land uses, and allocated land uses to the land response units for the study area. Six major land were considered in the study: forestry, agriculture, industrial/commercial, residential, urban, and fishery. Some of the ecological factor requirements of these major land uses and specific land utilization types were incorporated in the study. A new concept of evaluation was introduced to assess land uses based on their market and non-market benefits. The algorithm was also applied in land-use allocation using user-specified criterion which can be selected from the land-use environmental impact parameters. The algorithm is also capable of simultaneously considering the social, economic, biophysical, and ecological values of land use with the use of environmental impact indices. The algorithm works well in both bureaucratic and participatory planning and decision making by accommodating external value and judgement of the participating public</dcterms:abstract>
</dc:description>
<dc:type>U</dc:type>
<dc:type>E</dc:type>
<dc:type>V</dc:type>
<dc:format><dcterms:extent>356 leaves</dcterms:extent></dc:format>
<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
<agls:availability><ags:availabilityLocation>PH</ags:availabilityLocation><ags:availabilityNumber>8811859</ags:availabilityNumber></agls:availability>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="GB2013202139">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Better livelihoods for poor people: the role of land policy]]></dc:title>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Department for International Development, UK]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued>2002</dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[pro-poor]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[poverty reduction strategy]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Livelihoods]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Livelihoods.Agriculture]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Poverty]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[rights based]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Livelihoods.Social protection]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure.Communal land]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Governance]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[common property]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[West Africa]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land policies]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[urban areas]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Poverty]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Role of women]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[legal rights]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[women]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land use]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Geographical information systems]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description>
		<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Can pro-poor land reform reduce poverty?]]></ags:descriptionNotes></dc:description>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[This DFID consultation paper examines the importance of land, land rights and land reform in developing countries, and considers how land policies can contribute to poverty reduction and the achievement of the Millennium Development Goals. It advocates a rights-based approach to land through advocacy and representation of the poor in land management.The paper begins by outlining the benefits of secure and equitable access to land and good land and in this context discusses challenges and opportunities in developing pro-poor land policy: Key challenges are identified as:equitable access, especially for minority groups and women; secure tenure in land rights, including rights to common property and other forms of rights in land; governance, in particular the administration of land rights;  financial and political sustainability. The authors then look at the how these issues might be integrated into poverty strategies and discuss the implications for DFID policy and practice.Strategy considerations include:The expensive and long-term processes involved in land reform may present problems for planning and budgetary cyclesThe political nature of land reform means that the social impacts have frequently not been adequately assessed. Development partner coordination in the land sector has not always been effective and there has been a tendency for donors to support stand-alone, technically driven projects based on pre-conceived models. National stakeholders, including a wide range of government, civil society and community stakeholders, must be effectively engaged in the development of land policy. Governments should avoid raising unrealistic expectations, especially where powerful vested interests may be difficult to overcome. In these circumstances there may be a role for donors to support pro-poor advocacy and civil society groups provided genuine dialogue is facilitated.Land cannot be addressed in isolation from other sectors particularly agriculture, provision of basic services, financial services and access to markets. Poverty reduction strategy (PRS) processes provide a key opportunity. However land is one of the issues that many current PRS papers fail to address wellFurther comments and feedback are most welcome up to the end of December 2002, addressed to Julian Quan at:rl-policy@dfid.gov.uk. A final version of the report will be published early in 2003. ]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.dfid.gov.uk/pubs/files/landpolicyconsult.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.eldis.org/vfile/upload/1/document/0708/DOC11008.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:language><![CDATA[English]]></dc:language>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="US2012400695">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Social exclusion and land administration in   Orissa, India]]></dc:title>
	<dc:title>
		<ags:titleSupplement><![CDATA[Wage determinants in Cote d'Ivoire]]></ags:titleSupplement>
	</dc:title>
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mearns, Robin]]></dc:creator>
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sinha, Saurabh]]></dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorCorporate><![CDATA[Off of Sr VP Dev Econ/Chief Econ (DECVP)]]></ags:creatorCorporate>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[The World Bank]]></ags:publisherName>
		<ags:publisherPlace><![CDATA[Washington, DC (USA)]]></ags:publisherPlace>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Registration]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Policies]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Managers]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Farmland]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Orissa]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Rural development]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Marketing]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Legislation]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[India]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The authors report on the first   empirical study of its kind to examine - from the   perspective of transaction costs - factors that constrain   access to land for the rural poor and other socially   excluded groups in India. They find that: a) Land reform has   reduced large landholdings since the 1950s. Medium size   farms have gained most. Formidable obstacles still prevent   the poor from gaining access to land. b) The complexity of   land revenue administration in Orissa is partly the legacy   of distinctly different systems, which produced more or less   complete and accurate land records. These not-so-distant   historical records can be important in resolving   contemporary land disputes. c) Orissa tried legally to   abolish land-leasing. Concealed tenancy persisted, with   tenants having little protection under the law. d)   Women's access to and control over land, and their   bargaining power with their husbands about land, may be   enhanced through joint land titling, a principle yet to be   realized in Orissa. e) Land administration is viewed as a   burden on the state rather than a service, and land records   and registration systems are not coordinated. Doing so will   improve rights for the poor and reduce transaction costs -   but only if the system is transparent and the powerful do   not retain the leverage over settlement officers that has   allowed land grabs. Land in Orissa may be purchased,   inherited, rented (leased), or - in the case of public land   and the commons - encroached upon. Each type of transaction   - and the State's response, through land law and   administration - has implications for poor people's   access to land. The authors find that: 1) Land markets are   thin and transaction costs are high, limiting the amount of   agricultural land that changes hands. 2) The fragmentation   of landholdings into tiny, scattered plots is a brake on   agricultural productivity, but efforts to consolidate land   may discriminate against the rural poor. Reducing   transaction costs in land markets will help. 3) Protecting   the rural poor's rights of access to common land   requires raising public awareness and access to information.   4) Liberalizing land-lease markets for the rural poor will   help, but only if the poor are ensured access to   institutional credit.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:RN"><![CDATA[WPS2124Social exclusion and land administration in   Orissa, India]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www-wds.worldbank.org/servlet/WDSContentServer/IW3P/IB/1999/09/14/000094946_99060905321229/Rendered/PDF/multi_page.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[0-8213-1058-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Policy Research Working Paper]]></dc:type>
	<dc:language scheme="dcterms:ISO639-2"><![CDATA[eng]]></dc:language>
	
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[India]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="GB2013200349">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Botswana National Land Policy]]></dc:title>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Oxfam]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued>2002</dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[peri-urban land]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[urban land management]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land rights]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[urbanisation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[urbanpoverty]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Poverty]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land access]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land entitlements]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[rural land mangement]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Governance]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[SADC]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Labour]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[water supply]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[foods]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Poverty]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Role of women]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Disasters]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Development aid]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Climatic change]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[women]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Accounting]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description>
		<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Preparing a comprehensive national land policy for Botswana]]></ags:descriptionNotes></dc:description>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[This Bostwana government report  examines the linkages between land rights and both rural and urban poverty in Botswana, which constitute a strong element of the Bostwana PRSP. Its basis for this arises out of a  need to adjust the land policy and land laws, administration and management to the changes being brought about by economic development and associated urbanisation in Botswana. It considers a series of measures to tackle urban landlessness and the anti-social conduct of land hoarding and land speculation, proposes the following policy recommendations over a broad spectrum of issues, some of which include:  land rights of the poor - strengthen  planning and implementation capacity of land boards and councils to ensure that poor people have access to land.land rights for women - educate women and raise their awareness of their rights in terms  of existing opportunities and can make informed choices.land rights of minority groups - Upholding the rights of minorities to pursue a different life style and maintain a distinct culture from that of the majority  HIV/AIDS and land rights - which includes conducting a special investigation of the impact of HIV/AIDS on land rights, land use and occupation in urban and rural areas.Other areas that this document addresses includes land markets, and land taxation issues as well as urban and peri-urban land management issues. ]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.oxfam.org.uk/what_we_do/issues/livelihoods/landrights/downloads/botissue.rtf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:language><![CDATA[English]]></dc:language>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Botswana]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="GB2013202725">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[The impact of HIV/AIDS on land: case studies from Kenya, Lesotho and South Africa]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S. Drimie]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Oxfam]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued>2002</dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[HIV.Treatment and care]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[impact of HIV/AIDS]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land rights]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure.Land registration]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[HIV]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land administration]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Labour]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[water supply]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[foods]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Poverty]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Role of women]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Disasters]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Development aid]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Climatic change]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[women]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Natural disasters]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description>
		<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[How should policy-makers respond to the impacts of HIV/AIDS on land?]]></ags:descriptionNotes></dc:description>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[The paper presents case studies from Kenya, Lesotho and South Africa in order to examine the impact of HIV/AIDS upon land, and present preliminary policy recommendations.  It finds that as a direct result of very high infection rates in the region, HIV/AIDS will seriously impact on a range of land issues and livelihood strategies, including:different forms of land usevarious types of land tenure and land reform projects that are most appropriatethe functioning of land administration systemsthe land rights of women, orphans and the poor generallyinheritance practices and normsPreliminary policy recommendations are given for three areas:General recommendations:increase the capacity of households to engage in income generating activities, both agricultural and non-farm activities, taking into account the limited capacity of infected individuals and affected households in terms of labourincrease access to water for gardening purposescontinue with the sensitisation of people to the reality of HIV/AIDS and promote HIV testing and counsellingpolicies aimed at addressing the felt needs of the people infected by HIV/AIDS should be developedsupport home care and community support programmes, including conducting research into social policies that are sensitive to the impacts of HIV/AIDS on households' coping mechanisms (which may become overwhelmed)Fortifying land administration systems in tribal areas to take into account specific concerns around HIV/AIDS and land:strengthen the land registration system in tribal areas, in particular relect rights in land of women, adult children, and perhaps minorsall round strengthening of tribal land administration systems, for example, through training tribal land clerks in administration functions to assist tribal authorities to perform their various land administration functionsensure representation of weaker individuals and households in respect of land administrationfacilitate the development of land rental markets in communal areasStrategic interventions and actions to further ameliorate the situation in respect of HIV/AIDS and land:governments should acknowledge the impact that HIV/AIDS is imposing on its service delivery capacity, especially at the grassroots level, and thus put into place appropriate safety netsinitiate large-scale sensitisation and training campaigns for the benefit of traditional leaders, community health workers, traditional healers, social workers, agricultural extension worksrecognise the value of community health workers, and afford them a special measure of support to perform their rolestrategise with officials within agriculture and land departments to take better recognition of diverse household types that result from HIV/AIDS impactsconduct research on high yielding, nutritive, fast maturing, water efficient and pest and disease varieties of crops, which would minimise labour requirements, decrease duration of farm operations and improve affected household’s food security[adapted from the author] ]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.oxfam.org.uk/what_we_do/issues/livelihoods/landrights/downloads/hivsynth.rtf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:language><![CDATA[English]]></dc:language>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Kenya]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Lesotho]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[South Africa]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="GB2013202784">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Smallholder income and land distribution in Africa: implications for poverty reduction strategies]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[T.S. Jayne]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Department of Agricultural Economics, Michigan State University]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued>2001</dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[household poverty income]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land right]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Poverty]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Governance.Privatisation of infrastructure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[household poverty]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land reform]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[poverty alleviation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[poverty employment]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Governance]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Ethiopia]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Kenya]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Poverty]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Economic development]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land access]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Africa]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[food security]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Agricultural economics]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Income]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description>
		<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Do poverty alleviation strategies  make  land more accessible to smallholder farmers?]]></ags:descriptionNotes></dc:description>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[It has been argued that many of the poverty reduction strategy papers pay insufficient attetion to the role of land access and land distribution in rural poverty.   Redressing the inequalities between small-scale and large-scale farming sectots  is likely to be an important element of an effective rural poverty reduction strategy in countries such as Zimbabwe and Kenya.   However, within Africa’s small-scale farming sectors, surprisingly little attention has been devoted to quantifying land distribution patterns and considering how they will affect feasible pathways out of poverty.|This paper provides a micro-level foundation for discussions of land allocation and its relation to poverty within the smallholder sectors of Eastern and Southern Africa. Results are drawn from nation-wide houshold surveys between 1990 and 2000 in five countries: Ethiopia, Kenya, Rwanda, Mozambique, and Zambia.| The paper addresses four major points:<B>why geographically-based targeted approaches to poverty reduction  - e.g. focusing on marginal areas -  is likely to miss a significant share of the poor in any particular country regardless of targeting efficiency in these areas: </B> poverty among smallholder households is not primarily a geographic phenomenon. Most of the variations in smallholder incomes tend to be within-village rather than between village, or in other words, the poor are geographically scattered throughout all regions of a country. This has implications for targeting vulnerable groups. Targeting of vulnerable, resource poor  households requires greater emphasis on intra-community targeting, as a complement to regional targeting. This makes targeting more challenging and costly to avoid private trading disincentives, if the development of private sector-led input and food marketing systems is considered to be an objective of government policy. On the positive side, the fact that poor as well as relatively better-off smallholder farmers are located in the same areas is good news for generating multiplier effects from agricultural growth. <B>Why current enthusiasm for community-driven development approaches will require serious attention to how resources are allocated at local levels: </B> in all five countries there are serious disparities in incomes and land allocation at the local level. This may give pause to current development initiatives focusing on “community-driven development.” While it is possible that village-level disparities in incomes and land could naturally occur as an outgrowth of differences in capabilities and entrepreneurship across households, it is at the very least important to ask whether local or national governance decisions over time play a role in generating such disparities. The data presented here is unable to provide a clear answer to this question. However, the findings do emphasize the need for promoting greater transparency and equity in village-level resource allocation decisions if there is to be a serious attempt to combat rural poverty. This conclusion flows from the strong association between landholding size and per capita incomes, especially at low levels of landholding size. Over time, it is possible that broadbased economic growth coupled with education can help pull landless and near-landless households into more remunerative non-farm activities, lessening the importance of access to land as a dominant determinant of income levels. <B>Why meaningful poverty alleviation strategies in many countries will require fundamental changes to make land more accessible to smallholder farmers: </B> this paper highlights a major structural problem within smallholder agriculture in these African countries. Without major changes in access to land the following processes in these countries are likely to continue:farm sizes are likely to decline over time landlessness and near-landlessness will emerge as increasingly important social and economic problems unless growth in the non-farm sectors can be substantially increasedgiven existing agricultural technology and realistic projections of future productivity growth potential, large segments of the rural population will be unable to climb out of poverty through agricultural growth on their own farms.These findings reinforce the idea that where access to land is highly  concentrated and where a sizable part of the rural population lack sufficient land to earn a livelihood, then special measures will be necessary to tackle the problem of persistent poverty. Recent empirical results indicate a negative relationship between the concentration of rural assets and the poverty-reducing effects of economic growth. Structural transformation processes may be retarded in situations in which the distribution of rural assets are so highly skewed that a large strata of the rural population may be unable to benefit from agricultural growth incentives that would otherwise generate broad-based growth multipliers. In some African countries, the distribution of land and other productive assets appears to be more skewed than available estimates for Asia at the time of the green revolution as well as most of South America. Education, which played a role in much of Asia by allowing households to exit agriculture into more lucrative off-farm jobs, is relatively low in most areas of rural Africa by world standards. Improving access to key assets, such as land and education, appears to be necessary to translate agricultural growth incentives into broad based structural transformation.<B>Why sustained income growth for the poorest strata of the rural population will depend on agricultural growth in most countries, and why agricultural productivity growth, while most easily generating gains for better-off smallholder farmers, is likely to offer the best potential for pulling the poorest and land-constrained households out of poverty: </B> Sustained  income growth for the poorest segment of the rural population is likely to depend on agricultural growth in most countries. The literature on growth linkages indicates that the first-round beneficiaries of agricultural growth generate important multiplier effects by increasing their expenditures on a range of local off-farm and non-farm activities that create second-round benefits for a wide-range of other households in the rural economy. Income growth derived from agricultural productivity growth generates demand for non-farm activities that has absorbed the rural poor into more viable non-farm activities. In much of Africa, the consumption growth linkages have been found to be especially important  The extent and magnitude of these second round effects depend on a number of factors, including education, infrastructure, and institutional development, but importantly include whether the income stimulus is widely spread . The initial distribution of land and other productive assets, which clearly influences how broad-based the first round beneficiaries of agricultural growth will be. While sizeable segments of the smallholder populations do not have enough land assets to respond to “smallholder commercial agriculture” opportunities, the data suggest that there are smallholders with relatively more land and related assets, who probably can respond, and who are located in many of same villages as those who have relatively little land on a household per capita basis.  This finding holds powerful implications for policy if shown to be widespread, as suggested by the data. Dynamic labor and services markets, and other employment opportunities should be easier to create (other factors constant) in the very locations where some smallholders are investing and raising their output and productivity. Pro-active public sector investment and policy support in developing these labor and service markets will be a key determinant of the magnitude of the growth linkages to be derived from agricultural growth. [adapted from author] ]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://aec.msu.edu/fs2/papers/idp24.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:language><![CDATA[English]]></dc:language>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="PH19970072374">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Concepts and methods of land valuation in the land market of the People's Republic of China.]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Li Shuping]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorCorporate><![CDATA[Philippines Univ. Los Banos, College, Laguna (Philippines).]]></ags:creatorCorporate>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[1995]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC"><![CDATA[E]]></ags:subjectClassification>
		<ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC"><![CDATA[E11]]></ags:subjectClassification>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="esp"><![CDATA[utilizacion de la tierra]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="esp"><![CDATA[ordenacion de tierras]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fra"><![CDATA[utilisation des terres]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="esp"><![CDATA[administracion]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="esp"><![CDATA[mercado de tierras]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fra"><![CDATA[chine]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fra"><![CDATA[gestion fonciere]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[land markets]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fra"><![CDATA[marche foncier]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[land management]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[administration]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[land use]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="esp"><![CDATA[china]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description>
		<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Thesis (M.A. in Agrarian Studies). 5 ill.; 2 graphs; 3 charts; 28 tables; 29 ref. Received Sep 1996. Summary (En). (UPLB Call no. LG995 1995 A1L5). AVAILABILITY: UPLB, College, 4031 Laguna - Philippines. E-mail: lbg@mudspring.uplb.edu.ph]]></ags:descriptionNotes></dc:description>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[The characteristics of Chinese land market were that government plays an important role in the market and that only land use right can be leased and transferred. Three land valuation methods that have been used in other countries are currently practiced in Kunming. These are the comparison method, the income capitalization method and the cost approach. Land attributes, land use, external factors were selected as the variables affecting land value. Land attributes were categorized into size, location, accessibility and physical characteristics. The results showed that location, physical characteristics and accessibility affect land value and that there is no relation between size and land value. Different land uses commanded different values. Commercial lands have the highest value, followed by residential, industrial and agricultural lands, respectively. External factors consisted of government policies and the manner of land use rights transfer. Government policies affect land value through zoning, taxation and transfer of land use rights. Agreement between buyers and sellers was the only measure used to transfer land use rights in the present Kunming land market. The study concluded the following: 1) the method used in other countries was applicable to Chinese land market with regards to land use rights lease and transfer; 2) government was unable to control the whole land market, and 3) the use of only one manner in terms of agreement to transfer land use right could limit the further development in the land market of Kunming.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Monograph]]></dc:type>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Thesis or Dissertation]]></dc:type>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Summary]]></dc:type>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Non Conventional]]></dc:type>
	<dc:language scheme="dcterms:ISO639-2"><![CDATA[eng]]></dc:language>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="ET2009000153">
		<dc:title xml:lang="en">Land use/cover dynamics over a period of three decades in the jelo micor-catchment, chercher highlands, Ethiopia.</dc:title>
		<dc:creator>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Mohammed Assen</ags:creatorPersonal>
			<ags:creatorCorporate>Ethiopian Society of Soil Science</ags:creatorCorporate>
		</dc:creator>
		<dc:date>
			<dcterms:dateIssued>2006</dcterms:dateIssued>
		</dc:date>
		<dc:subject>
			<ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E11</ags:subjectClassification>
			<ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">P01</ags:subjectClassification>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND USE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">REDUCTION</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">WATER EROSION</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">SLOPING LAND</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">SOAKING</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">TERRE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">UTILISATION DES TERRES</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">REDUCTION</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">EROSION HYDRIQUE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">TERRE EN PENTE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">TREMPAGE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">TIERRAS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">UTILIZACION DE LA TIERRA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">REDUCCION</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">EROSION POR EL AGUA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">TERRENO EN DECLIVE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">REMOJO</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_4172</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_4182</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_6483</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_8318</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_7109</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_7127</ags:subjectThesaurus>
		</dc:subject>
		<dc:description>
			<ags:descriptionNotes>5 Figures</ags:descriptionNotes>
			<ags:descriptionNotes>1 Table</ags:descriptionNotes>
			<ags:descriptionNotes>21 References</ags:descriptionNotes>
			<ags:descriptionNotes>5 Figures;1 Table;21 References;</ags:descriptionNotes>
			<dcterms:abstract xml:lang="En">Aerial photos taken in 1966 and 1996 (scale 1: 25,000) were stereoscopically analyzed to determine the spatial and temporal land use/cover dynamics that occurred in the Jelo micro-catchment, Chercher highlands, Ethiopia. The results of the analysis were digitized with the help of Arc View 3.3 GIS software to produce separate maps for 1996 and 1996. Six land use/cover patterns, namely dense forest land, moderately disturbed forest land, scrub land, severely deforested land, cultivated land and settlement land were identified. The analysis indicated an increase in cultivated and settlement lands and a decline in forest and other non-cultivated lands over the 30-year period. The settlement land increased by 107% between 1966 and 1996, giving an average rate of 1 ha (+3.5% of the 1996 settlement land) per year. During the same period, cultivated land increased by 55%, averaging to 24 ha (+2% of the 1996 cultivated land) per year. Forest land cover decreased by 80% giving an average decreasing rate of 33.4 ha per year (-2.7% of the 1996 forest land). Scrub land and severely deforested land also showed decreasing patterns by 54% and 42%, respectively, between 1966 and 1996. The decrease in non-cultivated land cover patterns implies their conversion to settlement and cultivated lands. The increments in settlement lands implicate a growth in population size, hence demanding more cultivable lands, firewood, construction materials and land for settlement. These latter land use/cover systems have also expanded onto steeper and upper slope positions. As result, the process resulted in severe soil erosion as evidenced by formation of gullies. Obviously, wild animals had also been reduced in number and diversity due to deforestation processes. From the results of he study, it may be concluded that in the catchment land use/cover dynamics is caused by the interaction of physical and socio-economic factors.</dcterms:abstract>
		</dc:description>
		<dc:identifier scheme="ags:RN">Volume8, Number 1,June 2006</dc:identifier>
		<dc:type>J</dc:type>
		<dc:format>
			<dcterms:extent>39-56p.</dcterms:extent>
		</dc:format>
		<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
		<agls:availability>
			<ags:availabilityLocation>Eiar/Library</ags:availabilityLocation>
			<ags:availabilityNumber>ET2009000153</ags:availabilityNumber>
		</agls:availability>
		<ags:citation>
			<ags:citationTitle xml:lang="En">Ethiopian Journal of Natural Resources.</ags:citationTitle>
			<ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1563-3705</ags:citationIdentifier>
			<ags:citationNumber>39-56p.</ags:citationNumber>
			<ags:citationChronology>2006</ags:citationChronology>
		</ags:citation>
	</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="KE2007200105">
		<dc:title xml:lang="en">Land use and cover reconstruction: A case of kakuuto and bunha counties in uganda</dc:title>
		<dc:creator>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Isabirye, M.(Kawanda Agricultural Research Institute, Kampala, Uganda)</ags:creatorPersonal>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Magunda, M.K.(Kawanda Agricultural Research Institute, Kampala, Uganda)</ags:creatorPersonal>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Deckers, J.(Katliolieke University Leuven, Institute for Land and Water Management, Vital Decosterstraat Leuven,Belgium)</ags:creatorPersonal>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Poesen, J.(Land resources and farm planning unit, Ministry of Agriculture, animal industry and fisheries, Entebbe, Uganda.)</ags:creatorPersonal>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Ssali, C.K.(Land resources and farm planning unit, Ministry of Agriculture, animal industry and fisheries, Entebbe, Uganda.)</ags:creatorPersonal>
			<ags:creatorCorporate>Kenya Agricultural Research Institute, Nairobi (Kenya). National Agricultural Research Laboratories</ags:creatorCorporate>
			<ags:creatorConference>Sustainable use of land resources to alleviate poverty in the new millennium, 18, Mombasa (Kenya), 4th-8th December 2000</ags:creatorConference>
		</dc:creator>
		<dc:publisher>
			<ags:publisherName>Soil Science Society of East Africa</ags:publisherName>
			<ags:publisherPlace>Nairobi (Kenya)</ags:publisherPlace>
		</dc:publisher>
		<dc:date>
			<dcterms:dateIssued>2003</dcterms:dateIssued>
		</dc:date>
		<dc:subject>
			<ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E11</ags:subjectClassification>
			<ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E11</ags:subjectClassification>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND USE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND USE PLANNING</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND VARIETIES</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">GRASSLAND MANAGEMENT</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">GRASSLANDS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">AGRICULTURE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">GRAZING</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">UGANDA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">UTILISATION DES TERRES</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">AMENAGEMENT DU TERRITOIRE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">VARIETE INDIGENE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">CONDUITE DES HERBAGES</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">HERBAGE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">AGRICULTURE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">PATURAGE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">OUGANDA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">UTILIZACION DE LA TIERRA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">ORDENACION TERRITORIAL</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">VARIEDADES INDIGENAS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">MANEJO DE PRADERAS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">PRADERAS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">AGRICULTURA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">PASTOREO</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">UGANDA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_4182</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_37899</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_32886</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_3364</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_3366</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_203</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_25243</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_8038</ags:subjectThesaurus>
		</dc:subject>
		<dc:description>
			<dcterms:abstract xml:lang="En">Agriculture, grazing and burning are major land use activities that have transformed forest, Ihicket and woodlands to cropland and barelands over years. The cummulative effect of these transformaticns may have corttributed to extensive land degradation now experienced by farmers. Understanding the histcrical evolution of land use in the lake basin may assist in developing more appropriate farming systems better able to sustain dense human populatiens, alleviate deforestation and regenerate degraded land. Available histcrical Larid useJcover maps involved mapping of natural vegetation and land use separately. The natural vegetation map does not cater for certain aspects of land cover like bareland, built up areas and water bodies. We reconstructed land useJcover based on the interpretatien of panchromatic aerial photographs, development of a photo - key and field ground truthing exercise resulted into land use I cover maps 1:50,000 of two pilot agro - ecological zones within the Lake Victoria catchment. These outcomes were strengthened by informal interviews, identificatien of renmant vegetation and use of topographic map which were compiled using aerial photographs shot in 1954. A modified system of land useJcover classification was developed and used to describe and classify elements in this study. Emphasis was put on land useJcover - soil relationships; easy inteqretability using aerial photographs and satellite images and a clear distinction between land use and land cover. Based en this classification, eleven land cover types existed then (1954) and !hese include: Savanna, Aquatic grassland, cropland, swamp forest, bushland and thicket, bareland, ForesVsavanna mosaic, bWlled overland, built up areas. Related land uses include: mixed agriculture, rough grazing, food gathering, hunting and fishing, cortservation, forestry sanctuary, transport, and communication and settlement. Barelands may have existed for a century or beyond. The major causative factor then seems to be uncorttrolled grass fires that have cootrolled the dynamism of ecological succession. An understanding of the ecological and secoodary vegetation succession would greatly corttribute to development of feasible land management intervention technologies. This documentation can be used to study temporal and ipatial dynamism in land useJcover with associated changes in soil characteristics and quality as a result of human interventions through agriculture and grazing.</dcterms:abstract>
		</dc:description>
		<dc:type>K</dc:type>
		<dc:format>
			<dcterms:extent>p.411-421</dcterms:extent>
		</dc:format>
		<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
		<agls:availability>
			<ags:availabilityLocation>KARI-NARL Libary(NARL repository)</ags:availabilityLocation>
			<ags:availabilityNumber>631.4</ags:availabilityNumber>
		</agls:availability>
		<dc:source>Soil science society of East Africa proceedings of the 18th conference and end of the millennium celebrations, Mureithi, J.G.Machari, P.N.Machari, P.N.Mburu, M.Mugendi, D.N.Gachene, C.K.K..- Nairobi (Kenya): Soil Science Society of East Africa, 2003. Sustainable use of land resources to alleviate poverty in the new millennium,Sustainable use of land resources to alleviate poverty in the new millennium, 18, Mombasa (Kenya), 4th-8th December 2000.- 9966-879-51-X.- p.411-421</dc:source>
	</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="GB2013200237">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Land in Africa: an indispenable element towards increasing the wealth of the poor]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J. Negrão]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Eduardo Mondlane University, Maputo, Mozambique]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued>2002</dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[poverty]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Poverty]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land ownership]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Male labour]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[legislation]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Africa]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Capital]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[economics]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land use]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Sustainability]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description>
		<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Relationships between the poor, land and the market in Mozambique]]></ags:descriptionNotes></dc:description>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[The poor in Mozambique survive off the land, but what would the consequences be if the land was privatised? This paper looks at how Mozambique is approaching issues surrounding land usage and ownership as market reforms take place and the land becomes increasingly susceptible to being opened up to the market.A historical background to the issue of land use and ownership in Africa is given, from colonisation to the impact of globalisation and the market in present day Africa. The author suggests that:where the neo-liberal model of land reform took place, rather than land being used for productive ends, monopolisation and land speculation occuredthere were those among the poor who reverted to the condition of being ‘landless’, having to resort to leasing the land urban dwelling large landowners who invested nothing towards the improvement of the lands under their controlcredit did not flow as had been foreseen, because the commercial banks did not accept the land of the poor as collateralthe state’s compensation system for redistribution of land at the market price of the land ended up as a big problem for governments genuinely concerned with the welfare of the poorThe author concludes that:land needs public and private investment and, under current conditions, it cannot be transformed into goods that can be perfectly converted into capitalaccess to land must be guaranteed to all persons who wish to worksecurity of land tenure begins by recognising occupation rights and may be terminated by private appropriation with social limitations by the consubstantiated in the state’s institutionsland may and must be used as the poor people’s capitalthe persuasion mechanisms of the local institutions must be institutionalised into the administration of the physical spaceThe paper concludes by describing the Land Campaign that led to the building of an institutional framework encapsulated in the Mozambique Land Law of 1997 ]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.sarpn.org.za/documents/d0000101/P107_Negrao.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:language><![CDATA[English]]></dc:language>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Mozambique]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="GB2013201202">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Access to land, growth and poverty reduction in Malawi]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E.W. Chirwa]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Southern African Regional Poverty Network]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued>2004</dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject/>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Poverty]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Agricultural development]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Development policies]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Poverty]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[agricultural sector]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Income distribution]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Economic growth]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Malawi]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Structural change]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land use]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description>
		<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Pro-poor land tenure reform key to agricultural development in Malawi]]></ags:descriptionNotes></dc:description>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[After four decades of agricultural-led development strategies in the postindependent Malawi, economic growth has been erratic and a large proportion of the population live below the poverty line and studies suggests that the poverty situation has worsened. Agricultural policies favoured large-scale (estate) production at the expense of smallholder farmers who account for more than 80 percent of households. Smallholder farmers face several constraints including landlessness and small land holdings and declining agricultural productivity.This study argues that past agricultural strategies have been less successful because they ignored the land question among smallholder farmers. Access to land via agricultural production is one of the important factors that can translate growth to poverty reduction. For agricultural based strategies to be pro-poor in Malawi, land redistribution or resettlement programme for the landless or near landless should be central and a pre-condition for  the effectiveness of pro-poor growth strategies in agriculture. The econometric results of the study show that access to land reduces the probability of being poor; prevents the poor from falling into poverty; and helps the non-poor to remain non-poor. Since customary land is not marketable, the link between access to land and poverty is via the growth in agricultural production. Pro-poor growth strategies in agriculture are likely to be ineffective in reducing poverty unless land reform is taken as a basic precondition of other pro-poor agricultural strategies in the Malawian PRSP. Opportunities for land reforms, particularly those that can increase access to land for the landless or near landless, do exist with the resulting poor performance of estate agriculture. The problem of ethnicity in estate ownership is less relevant in Malawi, and some estates have been abandoned and other estate owners are offering their estates for sale. In addition, there is high willingness among smallholder farmers to participate in a community based rural land development programme. However, government has been slow in taking advantage of these opportunities due to resource constraints, the donor dependence of the land reform programme and the low priority accorded to land reform in the poverty reduction strategies. When funds do become available to implement a land redistribution programme it will be important to ensure that the process of beneficiary selection is clear and transparent, embracing the active participation of communities and that the programme need to place the whole rural development context into perspective both in the resettlement and emigration areas.  Ensuring that land redistribution is accompanied by complementary policies (such as promotion of land use, extension services, easing the credit and capital constraints and basic infrastructure that is conducive to agricultural  development) are also critical. Land reform is currently ranked a seventh strategy in the current MPRS, yet adequate land is a basic resource for any viable agricultural strategy. Arguably, agricultural based pro-poor strategies without addressing the question of access to land in Malawi will be as ineffective as they have been in the past four decades. The paper recommends that, as Malawi reviews her poverty reduction strategies, land reform should be the first ranked strategy for the agricultural sector to generate pro-poor growth. [adapted from author] ]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.sarpn.org.za/documents/d0001007/P1123-Malawi_Land_Chirwa_Aug2004.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:language><![CDATA[English]]></dc:language>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="ET2005000048">
		<dc:title xml:lang="en">Land tenure system and agricultural development in Ethiopia</dc:title>
		<dc:creator>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Klaus Deininger (World Bank Washington, Washington (USA))</ags:creatorPersonal>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Songqing Jin (UC Davis, Davis)</ags:creatorPersonal>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Berhanu Adenew (EEA/EEPRI)</ags:creatorPersonal>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Samuel Gebreselassie (Addis Abeba University, Addis Abeba (Ethiopia))</ags:creatorPersonal>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Mulat Demeke (Addis Abeba University, Addis Abeba (Ethiopia))</ags:creatorPersonal>
			<ags:creatorCorporate>Professional Associations Joint Secretariat, Addis Abeba (Ethiopia)</ags:creatorCorporate>
		</dc:creator>
		<dc:publisher>
			<ags:publisherName>PAJS</ags:publisherName>
			<ags:publisherPlace>Addis Abeba (Ethiopia)</ags:publisherPlace>
		</dc:publisher>
		<dc:date>
			<dcterms:dateIssued>2004</dcterms:dateIssued>
		</dc:date>
		<dc:subject>
			<ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E11</ags:subjectClassification>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">TENURE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND POLICIES</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND MARKETS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND OWNERSHIP</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">RURAL DEVELOPMENT</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">RESEARCH</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">ETHIOPIA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">TERRE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">MODE DE FAIRE VALOIR</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">POLITIQUE FONCIERE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">MARCHE FONCIER</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">PROPRIETE FONCIERE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">DEVELOPPEMENT RURAL</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">RECHERCHE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">ETHIOPIE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">TIERRAS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">TENENCIA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">POLITICA AGRARIA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">MERCADO DE TIERRAS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">PROPIEDAD DE LA TIERRA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">DESARROLLO RURAL</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">INVESTIGACION</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">ETIOPIA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
		</dc:subject>
		<dc:description>
			<ags:descriptionNotes>Summary (En)</ags:descriptionNotes>
			<ags:descriptionNotes>6 tables</ags:descriptionNotes>
			<ags:descriptionNotes>42 ref.</ags:descriptionNotes>
			<dcterms:abstract xml:lang="En">In this paper, we focus on the following issues: First, we are interested whether and to what extent land markets contribute to the dual goals of greater equity and efficiency in the rural economy. To assess whether concerns about a negative equity impact of land rental market functioning are justified, we explore whether such markets transfer land to households with lower land endowments and whether there is evidence of an "agricultural ladder" whereby it is possible for households to make the transition from sharecropping to fixed rent tenancy. To ascertain the impact on economic efficiency, we probe whether markets provide access to land for producers with higher levels of ability. We find that markets and administrative mechanisms tend to transfer land to more productive and poorer households. This would suggest that there is little reason to be concerned about potential negative effects of the emergence of rental markets as, with more and more off-farm migration and non-farm employment, the need for reallocation of land increases. A second issue to be explored, based on the identification of factors contributing to land access via markets in contrast to other mechanisms, is to compare the historical performance of land markets to that of administrative land reallocation. In addition to descriptive evidence, highlighting that rental markets have recently become quantitatively more important than administrative land reallocation, we find that reallocation appears to have been undertaken largely on political grounds, contributing neither to higher levels of efficiency nor equity. Finally, exploring factors that lead households to perceive a threat of future land loss (or gain)through administrative redistribution, we note that it is farmers who are more productive who have part-time jobs in the off-farm sector who perceive a threat of land redistribution whereas renting in land increases the expectation of gaining through land redistribution in the future. If, as is reasonable, households adjust their behavior to avoid actions that might increase the probability of them losing their land, this suggests that the danger of land redistribution is likely to retard the growth of the off-farm economy and, if realized, will also hamper agricultural productivity. This, together with the fact that it may be difficult to satisfy the expectation of those who expect to gain from administrative redistribution, suggests that a clear policy statement to reduce the scope for of land redistribution, together with proper measures to increase households' tenure security may have an important effect not only to increase tenure security and land-related investment but also to help jump-start off-farm investment and labor markets.</dcterms:abstract>
		</dc:description>
		<dc:type>K</dc:type>
		<dc:type>E</dc:type>
		<dc:format>
			<dcterms:extent>p. 40-65</dcterms:extent>
		</dc:format>
		<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
		<agls:availability>
			<ags:availabilityLocation>ET</ags:availabilityLocation>
			<ags:availabilityNumber>2005000048</ags:availabilityNumber>
		</agls:availability>
		<dc:source>Challenges and prospects of food security in Ethiopia, Tesfahun Fenta (ed.); Ethiopian Science and Technology Commission, Addis Abeba (Ethiopia)Osman Ali (ed.); Ethiopian Science and Technology Commission, Addis Abeba (Ethiopia).- Addis Abeba (Ethiopia): PAJS, 2004. Proceedings of the Food Security Conference 2003,Proceedings of the Food Security Conference 2003, Addis Abeba (Ethiopia), 13-15 Aug 2003.- p. 40-65</dc:source>
	</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="GB2013200412">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Rural land management in Zambia: the need for institutional and land tenure reforms]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E. Munshifwa]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Land Rights in Africa, Oxfam]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued>2002</dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land management]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land reform]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure.Land registration]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Agricultural policy]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land registration]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[common property]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure.Communal land]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[communal land]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Labour]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[water supply]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[foods]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Poverty]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Role of women]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Disasters]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Development aid]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Climatic change]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[women]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Accounting]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description>
		<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Customary system of rural land administration in Zambia, its effects and the need for institutional and land tenure reforms]]></ags:descriptionNotes></dc:description>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[This study contends that Zambia cannot develop if it neglects policy for the efficient utilization of its natural resources. One such area has been the absence of land policy for effective management of rural land.While failure in this area has been attributed to a number of factors, notably absence of credit and funding, this paper contends that the base factor is the absence of efficient land management for rural land.This paper attempts to show that rural land in Zambia remains undeveloped for a number of reasons:The absence of an institutional framework to guide land administration. No matter how much money is invested in the system as it currently stands, positive results cannot be guaranteed due to a very weak institutional base.The establishment of rural land management institutions would lead to a second phase of reforms - land tenure reforms. Prescribing the “right” land tenure system for rural Zambia is not possible in the absence of detailed field surveys. This presents a challenge to all researchers, NGO’s, government and stakeholdersThe paper concludes with a quote by West which it feels best sums up the findings of this paper:“Europe is at present offering two basic land tenure models to Africa, the individualist or the collectivist, and neither of them is immediately acceptable. The need for tenure conversion presents to African countries a unique opportunity for innovation, invention and planning. This opportunity must be seized in order to avoid not only the undesirable social consequences of unfettered private enterprises, but also, alternatively, the disincentives and diseconomies that have been found to accompany certain forms of collectivism”.The onus is on everybody in Zambia to assist in the directing of rural policy. ]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.oxfam.org.uk/what_we_do/issues/livelihoods/landrights/downloads/zaminsref.rtf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:language><![CDATA[English]]></dc:language>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Zambia]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="GB2013200650">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[The Reform of Rural Land Markets in Latin America and the Caribbean: Research, Theory, and Policy Implications]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E.B. Shearer]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S. Lastarria-Cornhiel]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D. Mesbah]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Land Tenure Center, University of Wisconsin-Madison]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued>1991</dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[markets]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Participation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Land reform]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Land ownership]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[All Latin America]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[informal land transfers]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[subsidies]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure.Land registration]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[market reforms]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Americas]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land markets]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[markets]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Latin America]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land access]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Marketing]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[tenure]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Caribbean]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Central America]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Journalism]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Summarizes recent research (to 1991) on rural land markets in the Latin America and Caribbean (LAC) region and on the relationship between this research and broader land tenure issues. The purpose of the project that prompted this paper was to carry out cross-country and longitudinal research on land tenure issues in the LAC region so as to provide an instructive and informative analysis of how tenure patterns affect economic, rural development, and environmental issues. The project's principal research areas were: (1) tenure security through improved titling and land registration systems, (2) the potential for farmland markets to increase access to land, and (3) second-generation problems of existing agrarian reforms. This paper summarizes the research undertaken by the Land Tenure Center on the second of these research areas. The studies reviewed are exploratory and are designed to investigate how land markets work in order to develop projects and policies that will make the markets more open and efficient and more accessible to land-poor and landless farmers. The paper is in six parts. Following a general introduction and discussion of the broad schematic framework which guided the fieldwork, section 2 discusses the constraints to small farmer participation in rural land markets. Section 3 examines the country study research carried out under the project, while section 4 begins the process of putting these studies into the theoretical framework needed for future research and programs. Section 5 discusses potential land market interventions, and section 6 presents the conclusions derived from the paper. The annex is an essay titled "Economic Theory of Land Markets and Its Implications for the Land Access of the Rural Poor," by Michael R. Carter and Dina Mesbah. [author] ]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://minds.wisconsin.edu/handle/1793/21901]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:language><![CDATA[English]]></dc:language>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Dominican Republic]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Ecuador]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[El Salvador]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Guatemala]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Honduras]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Saint Lucia]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="GB2013201988">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Land tenure and land management in the districts around Mount Elgon: an assessment presented to Mount Elgon Regional Ecosystem Conservation Programme (MERECP)]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E. Soini (ed)]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[World Agroforestry Centre]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued>2007</dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[uganda]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[deeds]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[stakeholder participation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[natural resource management]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land titling]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[kenya]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[ecosystems]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land use]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[east africa]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Development projects]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Kenya]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land management]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Role of women]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[tenure]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Africa]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Uganda]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Protected forests]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[women]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[agroforestry]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description>
		<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Stakeholder participation in land use: Kenya and Uganda]]></ags:descriptionNotes></dc:description>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[     This working paper reviews historical and current factors and patterns affecting land use, land tenure, resource access, human settlement, and conflicts over resource access and tenure in the districts around Mt. Elgon in Kenya and Uganda. The paper draws on a series of interviews conducted with government officials in the districts along with other support sources such as paper maps and existing GIS databases.<br /><br />Based on this approach, the common findings from this study in the current setting of land tenure and land management are:<br />                complex historical processes have led to the current state of land management in the two countries            land policies in both countries (Kenya&rsquo;s free hold tenure and Uganda&rsquo;s customary land tenure) have not resolved and will not resolve the land issues they were intended to address (such as low economic growth and agricultural production)            spatial differences in the Mt. Elgon area are the results of complex issues related to history, ethnicity and tradition, farming practices and development projects            emerging problem areas are landlessness, settlement conflicts, insecurity, fragmentation of farmland and small land size due to population pressure affecting land management, lack of tenure rights in practice (tree tenure and land rights) to women, conversion of customary land tenure into freehold, resource access to forest products (Kenya), and non-functional of land offices (Uganda).        The set of recommendations for modifying and harmonising policies and institutions - effective at the local level promoting sustainable land management in this area - are:<br />                freehold and customary land tenure system in this area are successful if the system is administered with principles of good planning, equity and transparency            improve the livelihoods and biodiversity by diversification            call for a total change in attitudes within families and communities            equate land rights for both men and women as legitimised owners            participation of communities and other stakeholders in promoting the management of forests            more scientific approaches to be called for in establishing sustainable levels of resource extraction.                     <span style="font-family: Symbol;"><span style=""><span style="font-family: "Times New Roman"; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; font-size: 7pt; line-height: normal; font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal;"> </span></span></span> ]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.worldagroforestry.org/downloads/publications/PDFs/WP15942.PDF]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:language><![CDATA[English]]></dc:language>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Kenya]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Uganda]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="GB2013203012">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Land in Africa: market asset or secure livelihood?]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J. Quan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S. Tan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C. Toulmin]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Human Settlements Programme]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued>2004</dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Indigenous Knowledge]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Livelihoods.Food security]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Agricultural biodiversity and natural resource management]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Food security]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Globalisation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Rural development]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Food security.Livelihoods]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Rural development]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Agricultural markets and food prices]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Land rights]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Food security.Livelihoods.Livelihoods agricultural assets]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure.Communal land]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Technology and innovation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Poverty.Rural poverty]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Land reform]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Agricultural biodiversity and natural resource management.Soil and land management]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Livelihoods]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Livelihoods.Agriculture]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Poverty]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Gender land rights]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Natural resources]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Peace and security]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Urban development]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Africa]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Agricultural policy]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Local government]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[tenure]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[legislation]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Africa]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[legal rights]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land rights]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Cadastres]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[registration]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land use]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description>
		<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Land reform and land rights in Africa: which way forward?]]></ags:descriptionNotes></dc:description>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[This document summarises the proceedings from a conference organised by International Institute for Environment and Development (IIED) , Natural Resource insitute (NRI) and the Royal African Society in November 2004.The conference brought together a wide range of interest groups including, African policy makers, academics and civil society representatives, as well as representatives of the private sector and international agencies, to debate the way ahead for land rights and land reforms in Africa.The event addressed two key dimensions of land and property rigths in Africa today and their implications for future stability, prosperity and reduction:    the links between propery rights, investment and the generation of econoimc opportunities in the context of global integration    how best to secure access to land for farmers and the urban poor as the basis for imporved livelihoods and food security.Emphasis was placed on sharing experience from a range of African countries and a series of thematic discussions focussed on:    formalising and securing land rights: diverse approaches from Africa    gender, land rights and inheritance    urban and peri-urban land development and land use conflict    securing collective rights to land and natural resources.In conclusion to the conference, the African Union recognised that for African governments to take the lead in land policy and tenure they need to:    give political support and long term commitement    break the barriers that current donor mechanisms present    put land issues into the wider economic development agenda    use the technical support that donors can provide    make training and capacity building essential skills to be learnt through learning networks and platforms    build and share models of innovation that are rooted in locally developed innovation    engage in policy dialogue to achieve radical new solutions to land issues in southern Africa. ]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.iied.org/pubs/pdfs/G00166.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:language><![CDATA[English]]></dc:language>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="GB2013203486">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[The political economy of land acquisition and redistribution in Zimbabwe, 1990-1999]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S. Moyo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Southern African Regional Institute for Policy Studies, Zimbabwe]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued>2000</dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[SAP]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[rrsouth]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land rights]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Land redistribution]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[ESAP]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land policies]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Government]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[markets]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Southern Africa]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land reform]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Governance]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[farming systems]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land use]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Zimbabwe]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description>
		<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[How land redistribution  was sabotaged by neo-liberalism]]></ags:descriptionNotes></dc:description>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Paper systematically evaluates the political economy of Zimbabwe's emerging land policy in the 1990s in the context of other land reform programmes in Southern Africa. Looks at: the background to the land reform process in the 1990s the government's consistency in addressing the land question through an empirical evaluation of the outcome of its efforts to identify land to be acquired compulsorily in the 1990sevaluates the policy on the basis of the government's own set criteria used to list the 1 471 farms, that is: land under use (including derelict land), multiple farm ownership, farmer absenteeism, contiguity to communal areas, and oversized farms in terms of their agro-ecological potentialthe socio-economic implications of redistributing the land that was gazetted for acquisition by assessing its quality, use and economic role, the extent of multiple farm ownership, and the social features of the identified farmsConclusions include:the government has a tendency to rationalise land acquisition and redistribution on the basis of historical grievances and political demands and not on the basis of existing valid economic and technical reasons for land reformthe absence of a transparent plan and policy dialogue process meant rumour and subjective interest rather than facts have led land policy discourses, affecting the credibility of the land reform process the land reform programme must enhance economic expansion and diversification through expanding production outputs in a more efficient and rational structure of farm sizes the dominant fear that state-led land reform will bring economic collapse is unfounded, given the social and political implications of a failure to address the land question [adapted from author] ]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.eldis.org/fulltext/moyo2.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.eldis.org/vfile/upload/1/document/0708/DOC8041.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:language><![CDATA[English]]></dc:language>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="Ph2005000156">
		<dc:title xml:lang="en">Barangay [village] land use planning: the Kaliwa Watershed experience</dc:title>
		<dc:creator>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Racelis, D.A,(Philippines Univ. Los Baos, College, Laguna (Philippines))</ags:creatorPersonal>
		</dc:creator>
		<dc:publisher>
			<ags:publisherPlace>College, Laguna (Philippines)</ags:publisherPlace>
		</dc:publisher>
		<dc:date>
			<dcterms:dateIssued>2004</dcterms:dateIssued>
		</dc:date>
		<dc:subject>
			<ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E11</ags:subjectClassification>
			<ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">P10</ags:subjectClassification>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">PHILIPPINES</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND USE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">VILLAGES</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">WATERSHEDS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">SURVEYS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">SOCIOECONOMIC ENVIRONMENT</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">PHILIPPINES</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">UTILISATION DES TERRES</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">VILLAGE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">BASSIN VERSANT</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">ENQUETE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">ENVIRONNEMENT SOCIOECONOMIQUE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">FILIPINAS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">UTILIZACION DE LA TIERRA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">PUEBLOS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">CUENCAS HIDROGRAFICAS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">ENCUESTAS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">ENTORNO SOCIOECONOMICO</ags:subjectThesaurus>
		</dc:subject>
		<dc:description>
			<ags:descriptionNotes>Summary (En)</ags:descriptionNotes>
			<ags:descriptionNotes>34 ill., 8 tables. Appendices. Received Oct 2004</ags:descriptionNotes>
			<dcterms:abstract xml:lang="En">A community-based land use planning approach was implemented in the Kaliwa watershed in Tanay, Rizal [Philippines]. The endeavor intends to institutionalize land use planning at the barangay level. Specifically, it seeks to assist barangays in the watershed delineate their respective boundaries, demarcate current land use zones, formulate land use regulations and prescriptions, prepares land use plan and construct  a 3D land use map showing proposed land use zones. Attempts to delineate barangay boundaries encountered difficulties due to decades-long land use disputes among several adjacent barangays. As such, it was decided to just gather relevant information that could be used by relevant government agencies to resolve the conflicts in the future. Current land uses were delineated using satellite and survey data. They were validated through ground surveys and community interviews. Current land uses serve as one of the bases for formulating land use prescription  and regulations. The land use regulations and prescription were formulated based on bio-physical and socio-economic conditions prevailing in the locality. Their suitability was determined using erosion modelling that allows determination of erosion potential of proposed land uses. The proposed land use regulations are the basis for identifying proposed land use zones in the barangay. A barangay land use plan was formulated to enable the local communities to institutionalize land use planning at the village level. The plan is based on land use prescriptions and regulations as approved by the village council. Barangay land use planning team was also organized in each community to facilitate the preparation of the plan and implement the proposed land use zones. Three-dimensional maps were prepared by the barangays in the watershed to enable the local communities to properly vusualize and successfully implement the proposed land zones in each village.</dcterms:abstract>
		</dc:description>
		<dc:type>K</dc:type>
		<dc:type>E</dc:type>
		<dc:type>V</dc:type>
		<dc:format>
			<dcterms:extent>30 leaves</dcterms:extent>
		</dc:format>
		<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
		<agls:availability>
			<ags:availabilityLocation>Ph</ags:availabilityLocation>
			<ags:availabilityNumber>*PH</ags:availabilityNumber>
		</agls:availability>
	</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="US2012418568">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Access to land in rural India - policy   issues and options]]></dc:title>
	<dc:title>
		<ags:titleSupplement><![CDATA[India - Karnataka and Rajasthan Dairy   Development Projects and the Madhya Pradesh, and First and   Second National Dairy Projects]]></ags:titleSupplement>
	</dc:title>
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mearns, Robin]]></dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorCorporate><![CDATA[Off of Sr VP Dev Econ/Chief Econ (DECVP)]]></ags:creatorCorporate>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[The World Bank]]></ags:publisherName>
		<ags:publisherPlace><![CDATA[Washington, DC (USA)]]></ags:publisherPlace>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Farmland]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Villages]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Economic competition]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Rural development]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Property rights]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[South Asia]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Markets]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Developing countries]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Legislation]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[India]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Access to land is deeply important in   rural India, where the incidence of poverty is highly   correlated with lack of access to land. The author provides   a framework for assessing alternative approaches to   improving access to land by India's rural poor. He   considers India's record implementing land reform   and identifies an approach that includes incremental reforms   in public land administration to reduce transaction costs in   land markets (thereby facilitating land transfers) and to   increase transparency, making information accessible to the   public to ensure that socially excluded groups benefit.   Reducing constraints on access to land for the rural poor   and socially excluded requires five key issues: restrictions   on land-lease markets, the fragmentation of holdings, the   widespread failure to translate women's legal   rights into practice, poor access to (and encroachment on)   the commons, and high transaction costs for land transfers.   Among guidelines for policy reform the author suggests: a)   Selectively deregulate land-lease (rental) markets, because   rental markets may be important in giving the poor access to   land. b) Reduce transaction costs in land markets, including   both official costs and informal costs (such as bribes to   expedite transactions), partly by improving systems for land   registration and management of land records. c) Critically   reassess land administration agencies and find ways to   improve incentive structures, to reduce rent-seeking and   base promotions on performance. d) Promote women's   independent land rights through policy measures to increase   women's bargaining power within the household and   in society generally. e) Improve transparency of land   administration and public access to information, to reduce   rent-seeking by land administration officers and to   strengthen poor people's land rights (and knowledge   thereof). f) Strengthen institutions in civil society to   provide the awareness, monitoring, and pressure needed for   successful reform and to provide checks and balances on   inappropriate uses of state power. In a companion paper (WPS   2124) the author addresses these issues at the level of a   particular state - Orissa, one of India's poorest   states - in an empirical study, from a transaction costs   perspective, of social exclusion and land administration.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:RN"><![CDATA[WPS2123Access to land in rural India - policy   issues and options]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www-wds.worldbank.org/servlet/WDSContentServer/IW3P/IB/1999/09/14/000094946_99060905321228/Rendered/PDF/multi_page.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[1-884122-04-3]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Policy Research Working Paper]]></dc:type>
	<dc:language scheme="dcterms:ISO639-2"><![CDATA[eng]]></dc:language>
	
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[India]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="LV2011000429">
		<dc:title xml:lang="en">Research on the preconditions of land consolidation in rural districts</dc:title>
		<dc:creator>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Platonova, D., Latvia Univ. of Agriculture, Jelgava (Latvia)</ags:creatorPersonal>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Jankava, A., Latvia Univ. of Agriculture, Jelgava (Latvia)</ags:creatorPersonal>
			<ags:creatorConference>International Scientific Conference: Economic Science for Rural Development, 12, Jelgava (Latvia), 28-29 Apr 2011</ags:creatorConference>
		</dc:creator>
		<dc:publisher>
			<ags:publisherName>[LLU Ekonomikas fakultāte]</ags:publisherName>
			<ags:publisherPlace>Jelgava (Latvia)</ags:publisherPlace>
		</dc:publisher>
		<dc:date>
			<dcterms:dateIssued>2011</dcterms:dateIssued>
		</dc:date>
		<dc:subject>
			<ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E11</ags:subjectClassification>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND CONSOLIDATION</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">RURAL AREAS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">FARMLAND</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND OWNERSHIP</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">FARM SIZE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">RESEARCH</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LATVIA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">REMEMBREMENT</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">ZONE RURALE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">TERRE AGRICOLE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">PROPRIETE FONCIERE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">TAILLE DE L'EXPLOITATION AGRICOLE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">RECHERCHE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">LETTONIE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">CONCENTRACION PARCELARIA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">ZONAS RURALES</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">TIERRAS AGRICOLAS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">PROPIEDAD DE LA TIERRA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">TAMANO DE LA FINCA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">INVESTIGACION</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">LETONIA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_4173</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_6699</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_2808</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_28718</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_2802</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_6513</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_12103</ags:subjectThesaurus>
		</dc:subject>
		<dc:description>
			<ags:descriptionNotes>Summary (En)</ags:descriptionNotes>
			<ags:descriptionNotes>1 table, 2 fig., 15 ref.</ags:descriptionNotes>
			<dcterms:abstract xml:lang="En">The concept of land consolidation is new in Latvia. Its main tasks are to eliminate land fragmentation and to facilitate farms of optimal size. One of the most important preconditions of land consolidation is forming of optimal size farmland plots in property and use, and land fragmentation, which has a major impact on both the operating conditions and other rural development processes. Land fragmentation affects not only land management, but it also increases transport costs. Already during the land reform in rural areas, land plots in property and land in use were divided per several land units. The other factor contributing to the fragmentation of farmlands is the development of land market, since it is not always possible to find land next to the owner’s farmland for purchasing or leasing the land to increase the land area. Within the course of the research, the analysis of the areas and fragmentation of economically active farms was conducted as well as the land owners were surveyed on variety of land use related and various rural environment characterising issues in Vircava parish. It was found that the growth of farm areas increases the fragmentation, and the results of the landowners survey show that the majority of the landowners are willing to expand their land plots in property, thereby increasing production rather than selling the land or leasing it to other farmers. Consequently, preconditions for land consolidation are being formed in Latvia as well as in other countries. It is important to find the most appropriate and efficient methods for their implementation.</dcterms:abstract>
		</dc:description>
		<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">978-9984-9997-7-7</dc:identifier>
		<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.ef.llu.lv/images/stories/faili_konferences/26_Sustainability.pdf</dc:identifier>
		<dc:type>K</dc:type>
		<dc:type>E</dc:type>
		<dc:format>
			<dcterms:extent>p. 174-181</dcterms:extent>
		</dc:format>
		<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
		<dc:relation>
			<dcterms:isPartOf scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.ef.llu.lv/lv/zinatne/konferences.html</dcterms:isPartOf>
		</dc:relation>
		<agls:availability>
			<ags:availabilityLocation>Fundamental Library of the Latvia University of Agriculture, 2 Liela iela, Jelgava, LV-3001, Latvia, http://llufb.llu.lv/</ags:availabilityLocation>
			<ags:availabilityNumber>04/362 Call Number</ags:availabilityNumber>
		</agls:availability>
		<dc:source>Sustainability. Economic Science for Rural Development. Proceedings of the International Scientific Conference, Mazure, G..- Jelgava (Latvia): [LLU Ekonomikas fakultāte], 2011. International Scientific Conference: Economic Science for Rural Development, 12, Jelgava (Latvia), 28-29 Apr 2011.- 978-9984-9997-7-7.- p. 174-181</dc:source>
		<ags:citation>
			<ags:citationTitle xml:lang="En">Economic Science for Rural Development (Latvia)</ags:citationTitle>
			<ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1691-3078</ags:citationIdentifier>
			<ags:citationNumber>no. 26/2011</ags:citationNumber>
		</ags:citation>
	</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="GB2013201888">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Landless women, hopeless women? Gender, land and decentralisation in Niger]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M. Diarra]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M. Monimart]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Drylands Programme, IIED]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued>2006</dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[mode of production]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Pastoralism]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[gender and agriculture]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Gender roles in agriculture]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[agriculture]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Gender.Poverty reduction strategies]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[women]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Pastoralism.pastoralism land rights and tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[ethnography]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Pastoralism.pastoralism gender]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[feminisation of poverty]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Gender]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[gender]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure.Land registration]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Institutions and policy processes]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[gender equality]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure.Communal land]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Pastoralism]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land management]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Role of women]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[legislation]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Africa]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[men]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[women]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[resource management]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Sahel]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description>
		<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Women's social exclusion from productive resources in Niger]]></ags:descriptionNotes></dc:description>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[This paper is a summary of a case study on gender, land and decentralisation. It addresses how women in rural areas of Niger deal with pressure on land within changing agricultural production systems. A separate focus is on women’s land rights, and the strategies they use to capitalise on these rights. The study is based on four main assumptions:increasing human pressure on land is changing dominant modes of access to land leading to the exclusion of women from agricultural productionthe decentralised system of land commissions in Niger potentially offer greater equity for rural womenchanging modes of production have led to the decline in the social  practice of  recognition for both men and women and based on merit. This is leading to new benchmarks for competition among womengiven the lack of non-agricultural economic options for women, poverty is becoming feminised. Women’s access to land is becoming an increasingly important issue for the land tenure systems.The four hypotheses are confirmed in the empirical study. The de-feminisation of agriculture is a reality, with women’s modes of access to land changing and the role of the land commissions and decentralisation still limited, constrained by traditional ideologies about leadership, status, and governance. For each study area, the paper finds women’s involvement in agriculture inversely proportional to pressure on land. Agriculture is becoming de-feminised in southern areas - where settled agriculture is the dominant form of production - and this marginalisation is having a devastating effect on women’s living conditions. The opposite trend is observed in the north, in pastoralist areas. Women here are excluded from keeping livestock and must resort to establishing agricultural fields in very marginal environments. In both cases, the most vulnerable women are excluded from the dominant system of production, where knowledge and social and economic valorisation are concentrated. A key conclusion is that the de-feminisation of agriculture is a determining factor in the feminisation of poverty.By way of addressing these challenges, some knowledgeable and wealthier women have adapted by gaining land via other socially-accepted means, such as inheritance but also through pledges and purchases. Nonetheless, the authors make clear that traditional models of female leadership and social-standing are in crisis, and emphasise that the political will of governments and donors is key to ensuring agricultural development in Niger is both pro-poor and equitable for both men and women. ]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.iied.org/pubs/pdf/full/12535IIED.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:language><![CDATA[English]]></dc:language>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Niger]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="GB2013203487">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[The land question and land reform in Southern Africa]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S. Moyo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Southern African Regional Institute for Policy Studies, Zimbabwe]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued>2000</dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[SAP]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Poverty]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[rrsouth]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land rights]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land reform]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Agricultural policy]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[povgdn]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[ESAP]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Environmental conflict]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land policies]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[markets]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Southern Africa]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[tenure]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Marketing]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Africa]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land reform]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[South Africa]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Zimbabwe]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description>
		<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Neo-liberal policy perspectives the major constraint to land redistribution programmes]]></ags:descriptionNotes></dc:description>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[This paper discusses the nature of the land problem in the region and tries to situate the general land reform process in Zimbabwe within a regional context.It examines the four key land problems facing the region the discriminatory and insecure forms of land tenure that are found among variouslandownership regimes  the increasingly imbalanced landownership structures and factors underlying itthe contradictory tendencies towards irrational land-use patterns through both the over utilisation and underutilisation of land the devotion of most prime lands and resources to production for external markets rather than domestic agro-industrial needsThe paper assesses the effects of these emerging land problems on rural poverty and land conflicts, as well as how existing land management systems address these problems.Concludes that the major constraint to the evolution of effective land redistribution programmes in the 1990s was the emergence and dominance of a neo-liberal, monetarist macroeconomic trade and investment policy framework.  Anti-state intervention or free-market policy perspectives reinforced in Southern Africa the biases against nationalisation or compulsory acquisition of land and promoted the current focus on market-based approaches to land reform.  Under this system,  the prospects for rapid redistribution processes  are not self-evident unless substantial external resources to pay for the land are introduced in the land markets. ]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.eldis.org/fulltext/moyo3.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.eldis.org/vfile/upload/1/document/0708/DOC8039.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:language><![CDATA[English]]></dc:language>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="JP2006001666">
		<dc:title xml:lang="en">Governing of land supply in Bulgarian farms</dc:title>
		<dc:creator>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Bachev, H. (Institute of Agricultural Economics, Sofia (Bulgaria))</ags:creatorPersonal>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Kagatsume, M.</ags:creatorPersonal>
		</dc:creator>
		<dc:date>
			<dcterms:dateIssued>Mar 2004</dcterms:dateIssued>
		</dc:date>
		<dc:subject>
			<ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E11</ags:subjectClassification>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">BULGARIA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND TRANSFERS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND MARKETS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">COOPERATIVE FARMING</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">PRIVATIZATION</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">SUPPLY BALANCE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">BULGARIE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">MUTATION FONCIERE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">MARCHE FONCIER</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">AGRI-EXPLOITATION COOPERATIVE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">PRIVATISATION</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">OFFRE ET DEMANDE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">BULGARIA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">ASIGNACION DE TIERRAS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">MERCADO DE TIERRAS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">EXPLOTACION AGRICOLA COOPERATIVA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">PRIVATIZACION</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">OFERTA Y DEMANDA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
		</dc:subject>
		<dc:description>
			<ags:descriptionNotes>Summaries (En, Ja)</ags:descriptionNotes>
			<ags:descriptionNotes>4 tab. 5 fig. 9 ref.</ags:descriptionNotes>
			<dcterms:abstract xml:lang="En">In this paper an attempt has been made to identify dominant forms and factors for land supply in Bulgarian farms. The New Institutional and Transaction Costs Economics framework is adopted to transitional agrarian economy. Institutional, behavioral, and transaction costs factors for evolution and sustainability of different forms of subsistent, cooperative, and commercial land supply in Bulgaria have been analyzed. Comparative efficiency of various forms for land supply in market-oriented farms of different type (unregistered, cooperatives, agro-firms) and sizes (small, middle, large) has been estimated. The study is based on original microeconomics data collected through interviews with managers of 0.5% of commercial farms in the country. First of all, a general characteristics and development of different kind of farms in Bulgaria has been presented. This analysis comprises: the kind of new commercial farms; the type of transactions under their management; the pace of evolution of market oriented farms; and factors for emergence of large-scale subsistent faming. Institutional and transaction costs origin of existing forms of farming has been underlined. Secondly, an analysis is made on major modes for land supply in commercial farms. It includes: the type of land supply (e.g. own land, leased land, cultivation in groups); modes of acquisition of land ownership (restitution, privatization, Purchase); extent of lease-in contracts; forms for reduction of land "supply" (sell off and lease-out land). Dominating modes of land supply are found to relate to critical dimensions and costs -of transacting. Thirdly, an analysis of the transaction costs in land supply has been made. It encompasses: the specific features of land supply contracts; the type of rent; extent of a third-party involvement in land transactions; and problems in land supply deals. Preferred contract forms depend on attributes of transactions and aim at protecting and minimizing costs of land deals. Finally, factors for enlargement of Bulgarian farms have been specified. It is proved that the reduction of land supply and the expansion of size of commercial farms, both have been determined by the transaction costs reasons. Presently, the high marketing, credit supply, and contract enforcement costs are the major factors restricting farms enlargement. A good part of cooperatives and middle-size farms also spend significant "time and efforts for finding partners selling or leasing-out land" On the other hand, the most important factor for farm development in the future relates to improvement of the institutional environment, and managerial experience of farm entrepreneurs. According to the farm managers there are no specific factors related to land supply which could impede farm development in the county.</dcterms:abstract>
		</dc:description>
		<dc:type>E</dc:type>
		<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
		<agls:availability>
			<ags:availabilityLocation>JP</ags:availabilityLocation>
			<ags:availabilityNumber>2006001666</ags:availabilityNumber>
		</agls:availability>
		<ags:citation>
			<ags:citationTitle>Natural Resource Economic Review - Kyoto University (Japan)</ags:citationTitle>
			<ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1341-8947</ags:citationIdentifier>
			<ags:citationNumber>(no.10) p. 71-94</ags:citationNumber>
			<ags:citationChronology>Mar 2004</ags:citationChronology>
		</ags:citation>
	</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="LV2005000397">
		<dc:title xml:lang="en">The factors of land use changes and its influence on the changes of unused agricultural land in Latvia</dc:title>
		<dc:creator>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Dambite, D.(Latvia Univ. of Agriculture, Jelgava (Latvia))E-mail:daiga.dambite@vzd.gov.lv</ags:creatorPersonal>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Vilcina, A.(Latvia Univ. of Agriculture, Jelgava (Latvia))</ags:creatorPersonal>
		</dc:creator>
		<dc:publisher>
			<ags:publisherName>Latvijas Lauksaimniecibas un meza zinatnu akademija</ags:publisherName>
			<ags:publisherPlace>Jelgava (Latvia)</ags:publisherPlace>
		</dc:publisher>
		<dc:date>
			<dcterms:dateIssued>2005</dcterms:dateIssued>
		</dc:date>
		<dc:subject>
			<ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E11</ags:subjectClassification>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Land use</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Abandoned land</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Farmland</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Soil fertility</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Land ownership</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Market prices</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Land management</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Economic analysis</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Statistical methods</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Latvia</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">Utilisation des terres</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">Terre abandonnée</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">Terre agricole</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">Fertilité du sol</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">Propriété foncière</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">Prix de marché</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">Gestion foncière</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">Analyse économique</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">Méthode statistique</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">Lettonie</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">Utilización de la tierra</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">Tierras abandonadas</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">Tierras agrícolas</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">Fertilidad del suelo</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">Propiedad de la tierra</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">Precios de mercado</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">Ordenación de tierras</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">Análisis económico</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">Métodos estadísticos</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">Letonia</ags:subjectThesaurus>
		</dc:subject>
		<dc:description>
			<ags:descriptionNotes>Summaries (En, Lv)</ags:descriptionNotes>
			<ags:descriptionNotes>2 tables</ags:descriptionNotes>
			<ags:descriptionNotes>7 ill., 8 ref.</ags:descriptionNotes>
			<dcterms:abstract xml:lang="En">The target of the research is to investigate the changes of types of land use and its influence on unused agriculture land areas in Latvia. During the research work author's analyses one of the important land use tendency that is to estimate the results of land reform and its influence on agriculture land and unused agriculture land, to find the fluctuations connections among these indicators in Latvia. Unmanaged areas are important problem not only in Latvia. The effect of unused agricultural land, changes in brushwood area, agricultural land market prices and the amount of permanent residents, have been researched by applying statistical methods (linear regression and correlation analysis). The results of the research indicate the growing of unused agricultural land areas decreases the quality of land as a resource and land fertility of land. Stopping the increase of unused agricultural land it is possible to improve the quality of land, increase its utilization and the market value, which gives grows of the fiscal value of the land tenure. With grows of the working places in regions also increases the amount of permanent residents in the regions, and will promote land management and prevention of rural landscapes.</dcterms:abstract>
		</dc:description>
		<dc:type>K</dc:type>
		<dc:type>E</dc:type>
		<dc:format>
			<dcterms:extent>p. 85-92</dcterms:extent>
		</dc:format>
		<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
		<agls:availability>
			<ags:availabilityLocation>LV</ags:availabilityLocation>
			<ags:availabilityNumber>2005000397</ags:availabilityNumber>
		</agls:availability>
		<dc:source>Rural development in the expanded Europe at the beginning of the 21st century. International Scientific Conference "Economic Science for Rural Development - 2005", Academy of Agricultural and Forestry Sciences of Latvia, Riga (Latvia)Latvia Univ. of Agriculture, Jelgava (Latvia)Estonian Agricultural Univ., Tartu (Estonia)Lithuanian Univ. of Agriculture, Akademija, Kauno r. (Lithuania)Warsaw Agricultural Univ. (Poland)University of Agriculture in Szczecin (Poland).- Jelgava (Latvia): Latvijas Lauksaimniecibas un meza zinatnu akademija, 2005. International Scientific Conference: Economic Science For Rural Development,International Scientific Conference: Economic Science For Rural Development, Jelgava (Latvia), 27-28 Apr 2005.- 9984-576-221.- p. 85-92</dc:source>
		<ags:citation>
			<ags:citationTitle>Proceedings of the International Scientific Conference Economic Science for Rural Development (Latvia)</ags:citationTitle>
			<ags:citationNumber>no. 8</ags:citationNumber>
			<ags:citationChronology>(2005)</ags:citationChronology>
		</ags:citation>
	</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2011100105">
		<dc:title xml:lang="en">Land tenure and rural development - Case of Slovakia</dc:title>
		<dc:title xml:lang="Sk">Držba pôdy a rozvoj vidieka na Slovensku</dc:title>
		<dc:creator>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Bandlerová, A., Slovak University of Agriculture in Nitra (Slovak Republic). Faculty of European Studies and Regional Development, Department of Law</ags:creatorPersonal>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Schwarcz, P.</ags:creatorPersonal>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Marišová, E.</ags:creatorPersonal>
		</dc:creator>
		<dc:date>
			<dcterms:dateIssued>(2011)</dcterms:dateIssued>
		</dc:date>
		<dc:subject>
			<ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E11</ags:subjectClassification>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">FARMLAND</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">OWNERSHIP</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LANDOWNERS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">TENURE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND MARKETS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND TRANSFERS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND ECONOMICS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">RURAL DEVELOPMENT</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">CAP</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">EUROPEAN UNION</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">SLOVAK REPUBLIC</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">TERRE AGRICOLE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">PROPRIETE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">PROPRIETAIRE FONCIER</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">MODE DE FAIRE-VALOIR</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">MARCHE FONCIER</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">MUTATION FONCIERE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">ECONOMIE FONCIERE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">DEVELOPPEMENT RURAL</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">PAC</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">UNION EUROPEENNE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">REPUBLIQUE SLOVAQUE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">TIERRAS AGRICOLAS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">PROPIEDAD</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">PROPIETARIOS RURALES</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">TENENCIA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">MERCADO DE TIERRAS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">ASIGNACION DE TIERRAS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">ECONOMIA DE LA TIERRA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">DESARROLLO RURAL</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">PAC</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">UNION EUROPEA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">REPUBLICA ESLOVACA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_2808</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_5466</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_4184</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_7669</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_4175</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_4181</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_25195</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_6701</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_1266</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_34779</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_33096</ags:subjectThesaurus>
		</dc:subject>
		<dc:description>
			<ags:descriptionNotes>Summaries (En, Sk)</ags:descriptionNotes>
			<ags:descriptionNotes>4 tables</ags:descriptionNotes>
			<ags:descriptionNotes>5 ill., 21 ref.</ags:descriptionNotes>
			<dcterms:abstract xml:lang="En">The structure of ownership of agricultural land, despite of the developing market with agricultural land in recent years, has not changed considerably. Most of agricultural land in Slovakia is, even after 6 years from the entry of Slovakia into the EU, leased. According to the Structural census of farms (2001), the lease of agricultural land represents 96%, in 2010 it was 91% (EUROSTAT, 2010). The research results obtained by Research Institute of Agriculture and Food Economics (RIAFE) indicate that from the total area of agricultural land used by the reference set of 6 regions for the period of 2001 - 2009 only 3.06% were owned by either individuals or legal persons who managed the agricultural land, and up to 96.94% consisted of the leased land. Similar results have been confirmed by the research obtained by Department of Law of SUA. As much as 75% of agricultural land is owned by private individuals, 5% is state-owned and 20% is still unidentified. It means that 25% of agricultural land which is managed by Slovak Land Fund remains under state control. This fact affects the market of agricultural land as well as the amount of the rent paid. There are still problems such as: high percentage of agricultural land under state management, fragmentation of agricultural land, unfinished landscaping, problems with determination of prices of agricultural land, different regional policies for tax collecting regarding agricultural land, limited possibility of acquiring agricultural land by foreigners. It is undisputed that the property rights to agricultural land and changes in its ownership and lease have an impact on rural development.</dcterms:abstract>
		</dc:description>
		<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.fem.uniag.sk/acta/en/15/acta_regionalia_et_environmentalica_%28online%29/content/2011/1/939/</dc:identifier>
		<dc:type>E</dc:type>
		<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
		<dc:relation>
			<dcterms:isPartOf scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.fem.uniag.sk/acta/en/15/acta_regionalia_et_environmentalica_%28online%29/home/</dcterms:isPartOf>
		</dc:relation>
		<agls:availability>
			<ags:availabilityLocation>Slovak Agricultural Library in Nitra, Štúrova 51, 949 59 Nitra, Slovak Republic, e-mail:slpk@uniag.sk, http://www.slpk.sk</ags:availabilityLocation>
			<ags:availabilityNumber>SLPK2011105</ags:availabilityNumber>
		</agls:availability>
		<ags:citation>
			<ags:citationTitle xml:lang="Cs">Acta Regionalia et Environmentalica (Slovak Republic)</ags:citationTitle>
			<ags:citationTitle>Scientific journal for regional and environmetal sciences</ags:citationTitle>
			<ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1336-5452</ags:citationIdentifier>
			<ags:citationNumber>v. 8(1), p. 6-15</ags:citationNumber>
			<ags:citationChronology>(2011)</ags:citationChronology>
		</ags:citation>
	</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="LV2011000801">
		<dc:title xml:lang="en">Problems and perspectives of land consolidation projects in the Republic of Lithuania</dc:title>
		<dc:title xml:lang="Ru">Проблемы и перспектива проектов консолидации земель в Литовской Республике</dc:title>
		<dc:creator>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Kavaliauskiene, B., Lithuanian Univ. of Agriculture, Akademija, Kauno reg. (Lithuania)</ags:creatorPersonal>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Tarvydiene, M.E., Lithuanian Univ. of Agriculture, Akademija, Kauno reg. (Lithuania)</ags:creatorPersonal>
			<ags:creatorConference>Baltic Surveying, 11, Jelgava (Latvia), 11-13 May 2011</ags:creatorConference>
		</dc:creator>
		<dc:publisher>
			<ags:publisherName>Latvia University of Agriculture</ags:publisherName>
			<ags:publisherPlace>Jelgava (Latvia)</ags:publisherPlace>
		</dc:publisher>
		<dc:date>
			<dcterms:dateIssued>2011</dcterms:dateIssued>
		</dc:date>
		<dc:subject>
			<ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E11</ags:subjectClassification>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND CONSOLIDATION</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">PILOT PROJECTS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND OWNERSHIP</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">RESEARCH</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LITHUANIA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LATVIA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">REMEMBREMENT</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">PROJET PILOTE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">PROPRIETE FONCIERE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">RECHERCHE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">LITUANIE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">LETTONIE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">CONCENTRACION PARCELARIA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">PROYECTOS PILOTOS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">PROPIEDAD DE LA TIERRA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">INVESTIGACION</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">LITUANIA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">LETONIA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_4173</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_36828</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_28718</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_6513</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_12204</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_12103</ags:subjectThesaurus>
		</dc:subject>
		<dc:description>
			<ags:descriptionNotes>Summaries (En, Ru)</ags:descriptionNotes>
			<ags:descriptionNotes>3 tables, 13 ref.</ags:descriptionNotes>
			<dcterms:abstract xml:lang="En">Since the year 2000 with the help of the specialists from the Land Consolidation Division of the Danish Ministry of Food, Agriculture and Fisheries, pilot land consolidation projects have been started. Besides the simple territorial readjustment of land parcels, these projects aimed to encourage local initiatives as well as to develop the land consolidation mechanism as an essential tool for the development of the integrated rural development including environment protection, development of infrastructure together with the creation of competitive farms. Experience gained during these pilot projects (cadastral areas of Dotnuva and Akademija in Kedainiai district, cadastral areas of Puskelniai in Marijampole municipality and cadastral area of Pabaiskas in Ukmerge district) was used when preparing legal acts regulating land consolidation. In Lithuania, already fourteen land consolidation projects (which were finished in October of 2008) have been started since the year 2006 following the provisions of the legal acts regulating land consolidation. The total area of the consolidated land covered 4827 ha, 380 landowners with 731 land parcels took part in this process. During the time of the fulfilment of these projects, in order to form land parcels of rational size and form as well as to expand agricultural land holdings, the number of projected land parcels has reduced by 219. Best results were achieved in the land consolidation project of Deguciai cadastral area in Telsiai district (which covered the largest territory). After the enlargement of the land-ownership, 67 land parcels were formed instead of 115. According to the National Land Consolidation Strategy approved by the Government of the Republic of Lithuania in 2008, it will be necessary to carry out the land consolidation gradually in the area of about 900.000 hectares. During the period of 2008-2013, it is aimed to increase the average size of the project from 300 up to 600 hectares, and the average size of the land holding – from 12 up to 20 hectares.</dcterms:abstract>
			<dcterms:abstract xml:lang="Ru">В 2000 г. начата разработка экспериментальных проектов консолидации земель по совместному решению Министерства Дании и национальной земельной службы при Министерстве сельского хозяйства Литвы. В проектах кроме переустройства и укрупнения территорий земельных участков, решались вопросы: поощрение местной инициативы, стремление развивать механизм консолидации земель, как инструмент интеграции развития села, в том числе охрану окружающей среды, развитие инфраструктуры, одновременно создавая конкурентабельные хозяйства. Во время составления пилотных проектов (кадастровых местностей Дотнува и Академия Кедайняйского района, кадастровой местности Пускяльняй Мариямпольсого самоуправления и кадастровой местности Пабайска Укмяргяйского района) приобретëнный опыт был использован при разработке правовых актов, регламентировающих консолидацию земель. 2006–2008 г.г. в Литве согласно положениям правовых актов, регламентирующими консолидацию земель, разработаны и осуществлены 14 проектов консолидации земель. Общая площадь консолидируемых земель заняла 4827 га, участвовали 380 собственников земли, имеющих 731 земельный участок. После консолидации на 219 земельных участков стало меньше. Наилучший результат проекта консолидации по занимающей наибольшей территории достигнут в кадастровой местности Дегайчяй Тельшяйского района. Укрупнив землевладения, вместо 115 землевладений будет сформировано 67 земельных участков. Руководствуясь Национальной стратегией консолидации земель, потверждëнной руководством Литовской Республики, консолидация земель постепенно охватит площадь около 900 тыс. га. В период 2008–2013 г.г. увеличится средний размер земли, от 300 до 600 га, а средний размер землевладения – с 12 до 20 га.</dcterms:abstract>
		</dc:description>
		<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://llufb.llu.lv/conference/Baltic-surveying/BALTIC-SURVEYING-2011-91-98.pdf</dc:identifier>
		<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://llufb.llu.lv/conference/Baltic-surveying/BALTIC-SURVEYING-2011.pdf</dc:identifier>
		<dc:type>K</dc:type>
		<dc:type>E</dc:type>
		<dc:format>
			<dcterms:extent>p. 91-98</dcterms:extent>
		</dc:format>
		<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
		<agls:availability>
			<ags:availabilityLocation>Fundamental Library of the Latvia University of Agriculture, 2 Liela iela, Jelgava, LV-3001, Latvia, http://llufb.llu.lv/</ags:availabilityLocation>
			<ags:availabilityNumber>11/796 Call Number</ags:availabilityNumber>
		</agls:availability>
		<dc:source>Baltic Surveying '11. Proceedings. International Scientific Conference of Agriculture Universities in the Baltic States, 11th - 13th of May, 2011, Jankava, A..- Jelgava (Latvia): Latvia University of Agriculture, 2011. Baltic Surveying, 11, Jelgava (Latvia), 11-13 May 2011.- p. 91-98</dc:source>
		<ags:citation>
			<ags:citationTitle xml:lang="En">Baltic surveying (Latvia)</ags:citationTitle>
			<ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2243-5999</ags:citationIdentifier>
			<ags:citationNumber>no. 11/2011</ags:citationNumber>
		</ags:citation>
	</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="PH2011000020">
		<dc:title xml:lang="en">Participatory-land use allocation in Besitang watershed, Langkat, North Sumatra, Indonesia</dc:title>
		<dc:creator>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Rahmawaty, Philippines Univ. Los Baños, College, Laguna (Philippines)</ags:creatorPersonal>
		</dc:creator>
		<dc:publisher>
			<ags:publisherPlace>College, Laguna (Philippines)</ags:publisherPlace>
		</dc:publisher>
		<dc:date>
			<dcterms:dateIssued>Apr 2009</dcterms:dateIssued>
		</dc:date>
		<dc:subject>
			<ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K10</ags:subjectClassification>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">WATERSHEDS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">WATERSHED MANAGEMENT</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND USE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">DECISION MAKING</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">PARTICIPATION</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND SUITABILITY</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">GEOGRAPHICAL INFORMATION SYSTEM</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">EROSION</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">INDONESIA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">BASSIN VERSANT</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">AMENAGEMENT DE BASSIN VERSANT</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">UTILISATION DES TERRES</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">PRISE DE DECISION</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">PARTICIPATION</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">APTITUDE DES TERRES</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">SYSTEME D'INFORMATION GEOGRAPHIQUE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">EROSION</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">INDONESIE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">CUENCAS HIDROGRAFICAS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">ORDENACION DE CUENCAS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">UTILIZACION DE LA TIERRA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">TOMA DE DECISIONES</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">PARTICIPACION</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">VOCACION DE LA TIERRA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">SISTEMAS DE INFORMACION GEOGRAFICA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">EROSION</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">INDONESIA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_8334</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_25301</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_4182</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_2147</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_37602</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_15992</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_35131</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_2651</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_3840</ags:subjectThesaurus>
		</dc:subject>
		<dc:description>
			<ags:descriptionNotes>Summary (En)</ags:descriptionNotes>
			<ags:descriptionNotes>Thesis (Ph.D. in Forestry: Forest Resources Management)</ags:descriptionNotes>
			<dcterms:abstract xml:lang="En">This study was conducted to develop a framework for participatory and improved land use decision-making in Besitang Watershed, Langkat, North Sumatra, Indonesia. Specifically, it aimed to: assess land uses changes, estimate soil erosion under different land uses, analyze the actual and potential suitability of the lands for several annual, estate and silvicultural crops, determine the current and potential land use suitability with stakeholder participation and develop a spatial participatory land use allocation based on integrated approach to ensure sustainability. Socio-economic information and physical data were derived from interviews and field survey. Collective opinion was derived from the workshop with stakeholders. Geographic Information System (GIS) and Analytical Hierarchy Process (AHP) were used for land use allocation. The Universal Soil Loss Equation (USLE) was used to determines soil erosion in each land system. Remarkable land use changes occurred from 1990 to 2006. Large portion of primary forest (82%) were converted to secondary forest, followed by conversion of mangrove forest into fish pond (30%). The mean soil erosion is classified as Class 2 and large areas are under suitable land uses based on erosion index. Land capability of Besitang Watershed ranges from Class 2 to 6. The majority of land is under the land capability Class 3. Land systems with very steep slopes were not suitable for several annual and estate crops and silvicultural species. In general annual and estate crops as well as silvicultural species are not suitable (N) in the lower stream of the watershed, due to drainage and flooding hazard. Alternative for forestry in Besitang Watershed based on integrated approach has very high suitability (63%). Agriculture use has high (63%) to very high (37%) suitability. Settlement area has low (23%) to moderate (77%) suitability. Fishery use has low (47%), moderate (18%), and high (35%) suitability. Industry has a very low suitability in all decision zones (100%). Based on allocation for multiple-use, Besitang watershed has very high potential suitability for forestry (63%) and agriculture (37%) land use. The most significant contributions of integrated approach using GIS and AHP in facilitating land use decision-making were: as a tool for land use allocation and policy formulation, as well as for scientific investigations. This approach provides participatory involvement of stakeholders in land use allocation. This approach is efficient and reliable land use allocation for watershed management, since it involves the physical components as well as participation of stakeholders to ensure sustainability.</dcterms:abstract>
		</dc:description>
		<dc:type>Z</dc:type>
		<dc:type>V</dc:type>
		<dc:type>E</dc:type>
		<dc:type>U</dc:type>
		<dc:format>
			<dcterms:extent>278 leaves; 50 ill.; 8 charts; 3 graphs; 86 tables, Bibliography (91 ref.). Appendices. Received Jan 2011</dcterms:extent>
		</dc:format>
		<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
		<agls:availability>
			<ags:availabilityLocation>UPLB Call no. LG996 2009 F648R33. *UPLB CFNR Library, College, Laguna (Philippines)</ags:availabilityLocation>
			<ags:availabilityNumber>2011000020</ags:availabilityNumber>
		</agls:availability>
	</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="GB2013202123">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Land rights reform and governance in Africa]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L.A. Wily]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[United Nations Development Programme]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued>2006</dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Governance Assessments.Assessing areas of governance]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Governance Assessments.Assessing areas of governance.Land governance.Assessing governance]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[customary land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land reform]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Governance Assessments]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[de soto]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Governance Assessments.Assessing areas of governance.Land governance]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure.Land registration]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Africa]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Agricultural policy]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure.Communal land]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[common property]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[property rights]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[customary rights]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[law]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Government]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[tenure]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[legislation]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Africa]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[legal rights]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Uganda]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Governance]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Common lands]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description>
		<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Highlighting the need to recognise customary land rights in Africa]]></ags:descriptionNotes></dc:description>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[The main argument of this paper is that insecurity of land tenure is a socio-political condition that can be made and unmade. This discussion paper focuses on customary land rights, particularly in the African context. The paper reveals that:    land tenure policies in the 19th and 20th century failed to recognise indigenous property rights derived through customary occupancy    these policies have deprived millions of poor of the protection they need to withstand the worst effects of social transformation and the commoditisation of land    20th century reforms often improved the access of poor to land through land redistribution and other schemes but made customary rights less secure    in Africa over 90 percent of the rural population access to land through indigenous customary mechanisms, and around 370 million of them are definably "poor"    while rights over farms and houses are not routinely interfered with, common property ownership of pastures, forests and woodlands see constant attrition through state appropriation and reallocation to investors or interest-holders of its choice    the lucrative and rising values of pasture, forest and woodland are still typically captured by governments in the form of logging, agribusiness land leasing and other fees depriving poor communities of a crucial capital base which could help them escape poverty.The paper indicates that there are a small but growing number of cases in Africa, where customary rights are now accorded equivalent legal force with those acquired through non-indigenous systems and may be registered under state law. Pointing to the need for a more action-based and community driven process, the author argues that this will:    better resolve conceptual confusions that still surround customary tenure and which frustrate sound policy development    trigger the local level empowerment and institution-building needed to more appropriately shape, drive and sustain political will towards real removal of the chronic tenure insecurity of the poor    limit the impacts of reform that is broadly market-driven and in the African context, often seeks more to bring as much customary land into the market place for investor acquisition than to secure customary rights and benefits    bring threatened commons to the centre of reform, facilitating the evolution of stronger constructs for the ordering and protection of collective rights. ]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.eldis.org/vfile/upload/1/document/1201/Land%20Rights.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.undp.org/environment/docs/slm/Land%20Rights.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:language><![CDATA[English]]></dc:language>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="GB2013202604">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Tinkering on the fringes?: redistributive land reforms and chronic poverty in Southern Africa]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A.O. Chimhowu]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Chronic Poverty Research Centre, UK]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued>2006</dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[poverty reduction]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[politics]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Poverty.Rural poverty]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[poverty]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Poverty]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Southern Africa]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land reform]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure.Land registration]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land policies]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Poverty]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Southern Africa]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land ownership]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[tenure]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Africa]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[South Africa]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Economic growth]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Zimbabwe]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description>
		<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Do Southern African land reform policies lead to poverty reduction?]]></ags:descriptionNotes></dc:description>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[In Southern Africa, landlessness due to the asset alienation that occurred during colonial occupation has been acknowledged as one of several ultimate causes of chronic poverty. Land redistribution is often seen as a powerful tool in the fight against poverty in areas where a majority of people are rural-based and make a living mostly, if not entirely, off the land. This paper examines the nature and extent of land reform in Southern Africa, with a particular focus on its contribution to poverty reduction.Clearly identifying the different types of land reform, the author examines the policy and practice in Namibia, Zimbabwe and South Africa. The analysis leads to the following conclusions:despite political appetite for deracialising land ownership, there is little evidence to show a commitment to link this process to poverty reduction - in all three countries in question, policy rhetoric on land as a poverty-reducing asset often has not been supported with a serious commitment of resourcesthe quality of land provided and the terms of access both compromise the ability of beneficiaries to ensure a secure livelihood - in this sense, the current conceptualisation of land reform does little to reduce povertyin all three countries there has been policy capture of land reform initiatives by members of the political and bureaucratic elite at the expense of the poorall three countries demonstrate a reluctance to meaningfully reform customary forms of tenure - there is, however, growing evidence of commoditisation of land under such customary tenure that may not always work for poor householdsthere is a significant lack of good quality data at the country level for the systematic monitoring of the impact of land reform - monitoring and evaluation systems seem to emerge as afterthoughts.The author concludes that, although some people have clearly benefitted greatly from land reform policies, there is no clear link between these policies and poverty reduction. ]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.chronicpoverty.org/pdfs/58Chimhowu.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:language><![CDATA[English]]></dc:language>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Namibia]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[South Africa]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Zimbabwe]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="PH19900091379">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Application of land use systems analysis to provincial agricultural development planning [Philippines].]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Clar de Jesus J.I.]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorCorporate><![CDATA[Philippines Univ., Los Banos, College, Laguna (Philippines).]]></ags:creatorCorporate>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[1988]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC"><![CDATA[U]]></ags:subjectClassification>
		<ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC"><![CDATA[U10]]></ags:subjectClassification>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="esp"><![CDATA[utilizacion de la tierra]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[demography]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[soils]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="esp"><![CDATA[arroz irrigado]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fra"><![CDATA[modele]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="esp"><![CDATA[recursos de la tierra]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="esp"><![CDATA[cultivos]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="esp"><![CDATA[demografia]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fra"><![CDATA[sols]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[land resources]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="esp"><![CDATA[modelos]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fra"><![CDATA[plante de culture]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fra"><![CDATA[demographie]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[models]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="esp"><![CDATA[filipinas]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[irrigated rice]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fra"><![CDATA[riz irrigue]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[crops]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="esp"><![CDATA[suelos]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fra"><![CDATA[utilisation du sol]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[philippines]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fra"><![CDATA[ressource fonciere]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[land use]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description>
		<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Thesis (Ph.D. in Soil Science). Bibliography (70 ref.). Summary (En). Appendices. Received Apr 1988. AVAILABILITY: UPLB, College, Laguna 3720 - Philippines]]></ags:descriptionNotes></dc:description>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[A land use planning framework patterned after a systems approach (Beek, 1980) applicable to fundamental provincial planning objectives in the Philippines and fitted to the available data sources was developed. The study highlights the conceptualization and development of the approach as tested on the conditions of Pangasinan [Philippines]. A database of three major files on land and soil qualities, land use and demographic variables relevant to the LUS [land use system] of Pangasinan was created to computerize the analysis. The land component of the LUS of Pangasinan was synthesized according to physiographic and soil qualities. The geographic planning unit (GPU) expresses this relationship and distribution of soils and physiography in a geographic continuum. The GPU defined the land development units which are homogenous land use planning area of characteristic land qualities and suitability for a set of land utilization types, specific crop rotation or cropping systems during the year. The land development unit (LDU) was related to the land use component through evaluation of its crop suitability to wetland rice, upland and plantation crops and land capability to produce one or more crop types or group. LDU evaluation segregated 292,363 hectares of the land resource base available for explitation with different suitabilities for production of the three crop groups. Land capability assessment in terms of the versatility of the land resources to agricultural uses recognized eight capability classes; the highest designation suitable for all crop groups considered while the lowest class fitted for preservation. Land use optimization and allocation show that Pangasinan has the land resource base to support the production of basic agricultural commodities to meet the needs of the population without deterioration of resources. Food sufficiency targets to meet the nutritional needs of the populace in 1990 may be satisfied even at the current rate of rice production. Additional opportunities for labor and rural employment are restricted by the availability of land resources due to the rapid growth of the rural labor force.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Monograph]]></dc:type>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Thesis or Dissertation]]></dc:type>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Bibliography]]></dc:type>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Summary]]></dc:type>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Non Conventional]]></dc:type>
	<dc:language scheme="dcterms:ISO639-2"><![CDATA[eng]]></dc:language>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="LV2013000290">
		<dc:title xml:lang="en">Description of land fragmentation in Latvia and its prevention opportunities</dc:title>
		<dc:creator>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Platonova, D., Latvia Univ. of Agriculture, Jelgava (Latvia). Dept. of Land Management and Geodesy</ags:creatorPersonal>
			<ags:creatorPersonal>Jankava, A., Latvia Univ. of Agriculture, Jelgava (Latvia). Dept. of Land Management and Geodesy</ags:creatorPersonal>
		</dc:creator>
		<dc:date>
			<dcterms:dateIssued>(2012)</dcterms:dateIssued>
		</dc:date>
		<dc:subject>
			<ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E11</ags:subjectClassification>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">AGRICULTURAL STRUCTURE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">FARMLAND</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">FARM SIZE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND CONSOLIDATION</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LAND REFORM</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">RESEARCH</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">LATVIA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">STRUCTURE AGRICOLE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">TERRE AGRICOLE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">TAILLE DE L'EXPLOITATION AGRICOLE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">REMEMBREMENT</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">REFORME FONCIERE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">RECHERCHE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="fr">LETTONIE</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">ESTRUCTURA AGRICOLA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">TIERRAS AGRICOLAS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">TAMANO DE LA FINCA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">CONCENTRACION PARCELARIA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">REFORMA DE LA TENENCIA DE LA TIERRA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">INVESTIGACION</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="es">LETONIA</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_202</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_2808</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_2802</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_4173</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_4178</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_6513</ags:subjectThesaurus>
			<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://www.fao.org/aos/agrovoc#c_12103</ags:subjectThesaurus>
		</dc:subject>
		<dc:description>
			<ags:descriptionNotes>Summary (En)</ags:descriptionNotes>
			<ags:descriptionNotes>1 table, 3 fig., 22 ref.</ags:descriptionNotes>
			<dcterms:abstract xml:lang="En">Already during the Land Reform, land properties of several land parcels were formed in the rural areas. Another factor that benefits to the fragmentation of farm properties is development of land market because buying or renting land for farm size building, it is not always possible to find adjacent land plot. Consequently, the land fragmentation not only makes land management difficult, but also increases the transport costs. With this rural land tenure system, competitive and efficient agricultural production cannot be discussed, so a large part of rural areas remains untreated. It was found that there is a strong correlation between the area of land parcels and their management – the smaller the area of a land parcel by the agricultural land, the greater the chance that it would not be managed, and vice versa, the greater the area, the more it is cultivated, that is, managed. Land consolidation is performed as the farm land use optimization activities in other countries. Land consolidation can be one of the efficient means for rural development, it can encourage formation of competitive agricultural production structure, giving farmers the opportunity to create holdings with a small number, but bigger size and better-shaped land plots. Thus, more income and opportunities to expand types of farming are created.</dcterms:abstract>
		</dc:description>
		<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.degruyter.com/view/j/plua.2012.28.issue-1/issue-files/plua.2012.28.issue-1.xml</dc:identifier>
		<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.degruyter.com/view/j/plua.2012.28.issue-1/v10236-012-0009-y/v10236-012-0009-y.xml?format=INT</dc:identifier>
		<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://dx.doi.org/10.2478/v10236-012-0009-y</dc:identifier>
		<dc:type>E</dc:type>
		<dc:type>W</dc:type>
		<dc:type scheme="isis">AS</dc:type>
		<dc:format>
			<dcterms:extent>1 Web Site</dcterms:extent>
		</dc:format>
		<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
		<agls:availability>
			<ags:availabilityLocation>LV</ags:availabilityLocation>
			<ags:availabilityNumber>2013000290</ags:availabilityNumber>
		</agls:availability>
		<ags:citation>
			<ags:citationTitle xml:lang="En">Raksti - Latvijas Lauksaimniecibas universitate (Electronic resource) (Latvia)</ags:citationTitle>
			<ags:citationTitle>Proceedings of the Latvia University of Agriculture</ags:citationTitle>
			<ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">8535 (Online)</ags:citationIdentifier>
			<ags:citationNumber>v. 28(1)</ags:citationNumber>
			<ags:citationChronology>(2012)</ags:citationChronology>
		</ags:citation>
	</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="GB2013200415">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Papers of FAO/SARPN Workshop on HIV/AIDS and Land, Pretoria]]></dc:title>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Southern African Regional Poverty Network]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued>2002</dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[HIV.Treatment and care]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[AIDS]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land rights]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[customary land law]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[tenure systems]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Poverty]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land access]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[gender]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Poverty.Household poverty]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[HIV]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land policy]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[property rights]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[entitlements]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Lesotho]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Colour]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land policies]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Kenya]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[HIV infections]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Poverty]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[FAO]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Africa]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[South Africa]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Climatic change]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description>
		<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[A review of the  issues surrounding  land use, HIV/AIDS and poverty]]></ags:descriptionNotes></dc:description>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Series of country papers on HIV/AIDS and land in Lesotho, Kenya, South Africa, Malawi, Tanzania, with concluding paper on methodological and conceptual issues. The key questions addressed include: The impact on and changes in land tenure systems (including patterns of ownership, access, and rights) as a consequence of HIV/AIDS with a focus on vulnerable groups. The ways that HIV/AIDS affected households are coping in terms of land use, management and access, e.g. abandoning land due to fear of losing land, renting out due to inability to utilise land, distress sale of land, etc. The consequence of such coping strategies on security of access and rights to land. The changes in land tenure, access and rights to land among different categories of people as a consequence of HIV/AIDS are affecting agricultural productivity, food security and poverty with a focus on women. The future implications for land tenure arrangements for HIV/AIDS affected households and individuals particularly of AIDS widows HIV orphans. Priority areas for policy interventions with concrete recommendations for securing the land rights of people affected by HIV/AIDS.[Author's abstract] ]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.sarpn.org.za/EventPapers/june2002/hiv/papers.php]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:language><![CDATA[English]]></dc:language>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Kenya]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Lesotho]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Malawi]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[South Africa]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Tanzania]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="GB2013200696">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Peasant Logic, Agrarian Policy, Land Mobility, and Land Markets in Mexico]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R.D. Quintana]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L.C. Bórquez]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R.P. Aviles]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Land Tenure Center, University of Wisconsin-Madison]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued>1998</dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Market oriented production and trade]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Land reform]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agricultural marketing reform]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Mexico]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land markets]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[markets]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[economic situation]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land tenure]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[indigenous organizations]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[indigenous peoples]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land reform]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[economics]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Structural change]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Mexican rural reform has questioned the role of the peasantry and private national producers in agriculture. The reform followed a neoliberal paradigm for incorporating the nation into the global village. As part of a government strategy, land reform in Mexico aims to change entrepreneurial and land tenure patterns in rural areas into an individual, private, large-scale, and capitalist productive structure, and the land market is vital in allowing the land transfers needed to change the land tenure pattern. Alternative land reforms favor a smallholding structure, and many academics, peasant and indigenous organizations, and even government officials, now favor structural changes that are related to the factors of production in rural Mexico and to the historical construction of the nation. This paper argues that the land market should have a vital role in an agrarian reform that favors the peasantry and indigenous people. There is a need to understand the peasants and indigenous people's logic, rationality and subjective construction of land, for land is the foundation of their survival strategies. The land market can answer to values that have deep cultural roots. The modernization of rural Mexico could be more inclusive, and the land reform strategy could be designed from the bottom to the top and consider the diversity of the rural communities.[author] ]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://ageconsearch.umn.edu/handle/12790]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:language><![CDATA[English]]></dc:language>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Mexico]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="GB2013201258">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[The impact of HIV AIDS on land rights: case studies from Kenya]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M. Aliber]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C. Walker]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M Machera]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P. Kamau]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C. Omondi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[K. Kanyinga]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Human Sciences Research Council, South Africa]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued>2004</dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Legislative process]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[HIV.Vulnerable groups]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[HIV.Treatment and care]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Women]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Land policy]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Vulnerable groups]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[HIV.Treatment and care.plwha]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[HIV/AIDS]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agricultural productivity]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Widows]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure.Land registration]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[HIV.Vulnerable groups.Orphans and vulnerable children]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Land rights]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[HIV]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Orphans]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[case studies]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[HIV infections]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Human immunodeficiency virus]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Role of women]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[tenure]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[surveys]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Children]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[women]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land administration]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description>
		<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[The inequalities of HIV/AIDS impact on land rights in Kenya]]></ags:descriptionNotes></dc:description>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[This study explores the relationship between HIV/AIDS and land rights in Kenya, with a particular focus on women as a socially vulnerable group.  It examines: the ways that HIV/AIDS-affected households are coping in terms of land access, use and management; the consequences of these coping strategies on security of access and rights to land; and how changes in land tenure, access and rights to land among different categories of people are affecting agricultural productivity, food security and poverty.  The report also explores the future policy implications for land tenure arrangements for HIV/AIDS-affected households and identifies policy interventions for securing land rights of people affected by HIV/AIDS.Recommendations for legislative considerations focus on the land-tenure insecurities of women and children as vulnerable groups, and under-used agricultural land in areas badly hit by HIV/AIDS.  Although the existing land registration process and dispute regulation serves vulnerable groups to a certain extent, the study identifies a number of shortcomings which need to be addressed. Finally, the study makes a number of recommendations for consciousness raising, including: a proactive communications policy; training on land policy, procedures, rights, gender equality, HIV/AIDS and stigma; and developing regulations to guide and monitor land officials’ performance. [adapted from author] ]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.fao.org/WAICENT/FAOINFO/SUSTDEV/dim_pe3/docs/pe3_040902d1_en.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:language><![CDATA[English]]></dc:language>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Kenya]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="GB2013201807">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Land tenure, farm investments and food production in Malawi]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E. Chirwa]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Chancellor College, University of Malawi]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued>2006</dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[agricultural productivity.]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Land reform programme]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[food production]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Non food products]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land ownership]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[tenure]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Africa]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[food security]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Malawi]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[investment]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land use]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Food production]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description>
		<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[A study into the unequal distrbution of land in Malawi]]></ags:descriptionNotes></dc:description>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[The unequal distribution of land in Malawi has been identified as one of the binding constraints on agricultural productivity and production. Most smallholder farmers hold land under customary tenure and own less than one hectare, many being unable to produce adequate food. In order to improve access to land, the Government started implementing a land reform programme in 2005 through a market-assisted, community-based approach to land acquisition. <br /><br />The main objective of the study is to highlight the impacts of the land reform programme on investments, food production and agricultural productivity. The study shows that smallholder farmers that participate in the community-based land development programme have increased access to land and financial resources, are more likely to invest in improved maize seeds, tend to be more productive, and have overall better welfare than non-participants. However, the econometric results show that these positive effects are driven more by access to the financial resources provided under the package of assistance in the first season, than change in land tenure per se. New beneficiaries with only one season of farming under the programme tend to invest more in hybrid maize and are more productive than those that have been under the programme for two seasons. <br /><br />The results underscore the importance of complementary investments and assistance in order for land reform programmes to have significant impact of poor smallholder farmers. The land reform programme in Malawi provides opportunities for the land poor and near landless to access larger parcels of land under the resettlement programme. Land relocation in the CBRLDP also implies change in the tenure system from customary tenure to leasehold as a transitional arrangement through purchase of underutilised estates offered by estate owners. If the appropriate legislation were in place, this land would have been under the customary estate tenure which accords usufructuary rights. <br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /> ]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.eldis.org/vfile/upload/1/document/1106/Land%20tenure%20farm%20investments%20and%20food%20production%20in%20Malawi[1].pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:language><![CDATA[English]]></dc:language>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Malawi]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="GB2013202119">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[The economics and politics of land reforms in Malawi: a case study of the Community Based Rural Land Development Programme]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E.W. Chirwa]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[B. Chinsinga]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[IPPG Programme]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued>2008</dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[population density]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[agriculture]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land reform]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[malawi]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[farming]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[case studies]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land policies]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Development policies]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[maize]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land ownership]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[tenure]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land reform]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land use]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Sustainability]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description>
		<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Possibilities for successful land reform in Malawi]]></ags:descriptionNotes></dc:description>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[It is estimated that up to 84% of Malawians earn their livelihoods directly from agriculture - it contributes over 90% to export earnings, 40% to GDP and accounts for 85% of total employment. While the advent of              democratisation in May 1994 provided a rare opportunity to address the chronic imbalances in the patterns of land ownership and distribution, the major development  strategies that the government has since implemented have shied away from addressing the land question.<br /><br />The Community Based Rural Land Development Programme (CBRLDP) stands out as the most significant intervention that has been implemented in postcolonial Malawi to address the highly unequal land ownership patterns. This paper examines the impact of this programme for the successful implementation of future land reform initiatives.<br /><br />The study demonstrates that success in promoting pro-poor growth and development is not merely a matter of conjuring good institutions - their design and implementation critically depends on agents and agencies to implement them. Key policy implications include:<br />    land reforms without a well-thought-out supportive infrastructure in the short to medium terms are unlikely to be sustainable. This is to say that land reform is more than just access to land: it must be accompanied by access to non-land assets; access to credit; access to extension  services; and training of beneficiaries in modern farming techniques    the functioning of other markets such as transport, output, labour and financial are critical for households to maximise the benefits from access to land and improved tenure security. Reforms of this nature are therefore unlikely to generate substantial benefits in terms of investments, incomes and sustainable livelihoods without the accompanying financial assistance to farmers through access to other agricultural inputssuch as fertilisers and improved seeds    a gender-balanced selection of beneficiaries would enhance the positive impact of the CBRLDP. The participation of female headed households in the CBRLDP is limited yet the economic analysis reveals that male headed households invest less in hybrid maize production compared to femaleheaded households. The level of education of  households is also important. The higher the level of education of the household the higher the uptake of modern technology such as hybrid maize and chemical fertiliser    the range of stakeholders involved matters in determining outcomes, successes and failures. Understanding the interface between formal and informal institutions in the context of the reforms is vital particularly in terms of anticipating and dealing with unexpected consequences.<br /> ]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.research4development.info/PDF/Outputs/ProPoor_RPC/IPPGBP20.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:language><![CDATA[English]]></dc:language>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Malawi]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="GB2013203310">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Rural land certification in Ethiopia: process, initial impact, and implications for other African countries]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[K. Deininger]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D. A. Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S. Holden]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[World Bank]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued>2007</dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[poverty reduction]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[participatory nature]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[low cost]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[characteristics]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[data]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[land reform]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[women]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[process]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[certification]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[pro-poor land laws]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Norway.Agriculture]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Ethiopia]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[village]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[impact, implications]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[rural land certification]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[African countries]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure.Land registration]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Africa]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Norway]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food.Land tenure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[household-level]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[data collection]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land policies]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Ethiopia]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Role of women]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[surveys]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Certification]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[women]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[surveying]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land use]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description>
		<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Understanding the effects of pro-poor land laws in Africa]]></ags:descriptionNotes></dc:description>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Although many African countries have adopted highly innovative and pro-poor land laws, lack of implementation hinders their potentially far-reaching impact on productivity, poverty reduction, and governance. <br /><br />To assess the effects of these pro-poor land laws and analyse whether the existing doubts are justified, this report draws on the experience of Ethiopia which, over a period of 2-3 years, registered the majority of rural lands in a rapid process at rather low cost. <br /><br />This report discusses the challenges for land policy and administration in Africa together with recent initiatives to reform legal frameworks and establish accessible institutions in response to these. Against this background, it describes key characteristics of Ethiopia&rsquo;s land policy and its recent certification process. <br /><br />The report then uses village- and household-level data to describe the extent to which different stages of certification were implemented as planned and to explore the extent to which these varied along lines of gender or wealth. <br /><br />The report also provides evidence on impact as well as costs of first-time registration as carried out now and with a spatial reference added and discusses options to ensure that the information generated is kept up to date and can sustain itself based on user fees. <br /><br />Lastly the report presents conclusions and policy implications, which are targeted at individuals interested in replicating or improving these land reforms in other African contexts: <br /><br />    the rapid speed, participatory nature, and low cost of Ethiopia&rsquo;s land certification, together with the positive results from this process and the absence of bias in favor of the wealthy or lack of access to information by the poor, demonstrate that large-scale and rapid delivery of land certificates in a participatory way is possible <br />    users&rsquo; positive assessment of the process, readiness to pay to replace lost certificates, high demand - and willingness to pay - for a spatial reference, and their positive assessment of likely impacts suggest that the way in which Ethiopia implemented land certification responded to local needs <br />    the fact that most disputes were resolved in the field, reinforced by initial evidence of positive investment- and transfer-effects, suggests that elements of Ethiopia&rsquo;s certification process, with modifications as needed, could serve as a model for other African countries to quickly scale up implementation of land legislation, the innovative provisions of which have thus far been largely ineffective.  ]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www-wds.worldbank.org/servlet/WDSContentServer/IW3P/IB/2007/04/19/000016406_20070419124805/Rendered/PDF/wps4218.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:language><![CDATA[English]]></dc:language>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Ethiopia]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="GB2013203199">
	<dc:title xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Agros International white paper: a review of land reform methods]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A. Dimmitt]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Agros International]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued>2008</dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture and food]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agricultural Development]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Land Reform]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Governance]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Poverty Alleviation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Central America]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land improvement]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Government]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Poverty]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Land ownership]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Latin America]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[tenure]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[land reform]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Governance]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
		<ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[Sustainability]]></ags:subjectThesaurus>
	</dc:subject>
	<dc:description>
		<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[<p>An alternative method of land reform for Latin America?<br /></p>]]></ags:descriptionNotes></dc:description>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[This white paper&nbsp;looks at&nbsp;one example of private land reform, Agros International, within the context of&nbsp;the global and historical scope of land reform methods.<br /><br />The paper states that methods of land reform can be understood within three general categories: government-directed reform, popular social mobilization, and market -based reform. However, despite the many benefits of secure land access, the application of effective land reform has proven difficult and rare. In light of this, it argues, private nonprofits and coalitions are essential to the research and application of effective land reform methods. <br /><br />Agros International addresses rural poverty in Latin America through private market-based land reform, established on a foundation of community planning and holistic development support. The organisation acts as a facilitator to meet the inadequacies of simply allowing the market to dictate the process of land reform. It mediates land purchase, provides loans for land ownership and infrastructure, supports the development and training needed to establish economically sustainable farming communities, and facilitates processes of community planning that prepare communities to become self-managing and self sufficient. <br />The Agros model, they assert, reveals the weaknesses of traditional methods, offers practical solutions, and provides insight that can be carefully applied elsewhere. <br /><br />Among the conclusion are:     contextualising current choices of land reform methods in an understanding of the history and global scope of these movements will contribute to greater success in developing effective solutions as regions and populations are specific, with unique histories, needs, and desires, and will require distinct applications of land reform methods that address their particular identities<br />    in the context of the three main categories of land reform methods, the Agros model, the author asserts, stands out as one that utilises practical methods of market-led reform yet fills gaps left by the standard application. It uses markets as a tool to meet the needs of people, rather than allowing markets to be an end in themselves<br />    Agros' strengths must be understood within its particular context where government-led land reforms have failed and social movements have proved only marginally effective in the face of often oppressive and unstable states <br /><br /> ]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.agros.org/downloads/AgrosWhitePaper_LandReform.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:language><![CDATA[English]]></dc:language>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[El Salvador]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Guatemala]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Honduras]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Mexico]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
	<dc:coverage><dcterms:spatial scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[Nicaragua]]></dcterms:spatial></dc:coverage>
</ags:resource>

</ags:resources> 